<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
    <title>Philosophocle</title>
    <link href="http://holdenlee.github.io/philosophocle/atom.xml" rel="self" />
    <link href="http://holdenlee.github.io/philosophocle" />
    <id>http://holdenlee.github.io/philosophocle/atom.xml</id>
    <author>
        <name>Scholars of Philosophocle</name>
        <email></email>
    </author>
    <updated>2016-02-20T00:00:00Z</updated>
    <entry>
    <title>PHSS</title>
    <link href="http://holdenlee.github.io/philosophocle/posts/PHSS.html" />
    <id>http://holdenlee.github.io/philosophocle/posts/PHSS.html</id>
    <published>2016-02-20T00:00:00Z</published>
    <updated>2016-02-20T00:00:00Z</updated>
    <summary type="html"><![CDATA[
<div class="container">
  <div id="content">
    <div class="page header">
      <h1>PHSS</h1>
    </div>
    <div class="info">
      
       
        <p class="subs">by Fron
	</p>
      
       
        <p class="subs">on 2016-02-20
	</p>
      
    </div>
    
  </div>
  <!--/div-->

  <hr>

  

  <div class="blog-main">
    <p>Studying late at night, it can be tempting to turn on the radio to see what is playing from the school’s station, PHSS (pronounced, “fiss”). At 3 or 4 in the morning, the programs are often unconventional. <!--more--> One day it might be “Mocha moves dance music,” another day it might be one student’s sleepless soliloquy on the current state of the world, another day it might be “the sound of various things dropping, like pins, toilet paper rolls, and feathers,” on another, it might be a student reciting a book of “American Knock-knock jokes.” It is fascinating, during those early-morning nights when one feels that one is the only person alive in the world, to feel oneself a periphery as one tunes in to the story of another’s life - or as much of it as can be inferred from the crackly soundwaves.</p>
<p>I discovered these programs when, one night, grabbing my alarm-clock-cum-radio from my bedside table to check my remaining time to sleep before my early flight, accidentally hit the “on” switch. I soon forgot all about sleep as I listened to a mellifluous voice talking about various luminescent creatures in the deep sea. Those soundwaves have echoed in my head as I traveled from Philosophocle, and became a symbol for nostalgia: for in my travels abroad, I have never heard a voice so content with esoterica as the mysterious stranger on that radio whom I have never been able to identify.</p>
<p>Since then I have been a follower of this unnamed radio hour, “programming” my radio to turn on for one hour and whisper into my pillow. Many times, some of the words warp into my dreams. Once, however, I was jolted awake by a voice unlike any I had heard previously, “You know what, no one is listening at this time of night anyway, so I can do whatever I want! I think I’m going to play this favorite tune of mine, it’s called armpit farting, by Yours Truly!” I need not describe the cacophony that followed; I had to shut off the radio and whisper “luminescent jellyfish” a few hundred times before I could fall asleep again.</p>
<p>When I woke up, I prepared to let the radio program be a forgotten nightmare. Imagine my horror when, arriving at Introduction to Data Science just in time as the teacher started lecture (using the methods of the course, over a period of 20 days I had found the exact second I should leave the dorm to arrive on time to class 95% of the time), to find that the entire front row of students had started to engage in that vulgar activity, and the rest of the class erupting in laughs, some genuine and some uneasy! I had always thought that I was one of few that listened to the unnamed radio hour, but now I realized my error in thinking that something so interesting could escape the attention of students who fed on soul-enlightening moments. (It is the same error of romanticizing that one is the only person in existence late at night.) The whole incident had become “viral,” and a quite many people had obtained recordings of the 11:58 performance, much to my dismay in the rest of the classes. I wished I could be as nonchalant as the professors, who knew that to object was the fan the flames of student ridicule (“throwing nuts from heaven”), but could only, alas, whisper “luminescent jellyfish” to myself.</p>
<p>No one was happier about the incident than Yano, whose thesis had been “Virality as a natural phenomenon.” We had prided ourselves on the resistance of Philosophocle to the crass forms of virality that, in the outside, digitized world, was symptomatic of attention deficit disorder, temptation irresistance, and a general sense of modern meaninglessness, so Yano had little to write about until today, when he can be found dashing from classroom to dining area to common room with a recorder on hand, cataloguing the first viral outbreak as it occurred.</p>

  </div>

    

    <!-- Extension : Sharing buttons @ www.sharethis.com -->
    <span class='st_facebook_large' displayText='Facebook'></span>
    <span class='st_twitter_large' displayText='Tweet'></span>
    <span class='st_googleplus_large' displayText='Google +'></span>
    <span class='st_reddit_large' displayText='Reddit'></span>
    <span class='st__large' displayText=''></span>

    <div id="disqus_thread"></div>
    


  
    <script>!function(d,s,id){var js,fjs=d.getElementsByTagName(s)[0],p=/^http:/.test(d.location)?'http':'https';if(!d.getElementById(id)){js=d.createElement(s);js.id=id;js.src=p+'://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js';fjs.parentNode.insertBefore(js,fjs);}}(document, 'script', 'twitter-wjs');</script>
  </div>
  
</div>
]]></summary>
</entry>
<entry>
    <title>The Street</title>
    <link href="http://holdenlee.github.io/philosophocle/posts/the-street.html" />
    <id>http://holdenlee.github.io/philosophocle/posts/the-street.html</id>
    <published>2016-02-19T00:00:00Z</published>
    <updated>2016-02-19T00:00:00Z</updated>
    <summary type="html"><![CDATA[
<div class="container">
  <div id="content">
    <div class="page header">
      <h1>The Street</h1>
    </div>
    <div class="info">
      
       
        <p class="subs">by Professor Wyse
	</p>
      
       
        <p class="subs">on 2016-02-19
	</p>
      
    </div>
    
  </div>
  <!--/div-->

  <hr>

  

  <div class="blog-main">
    <p>In Philosophocle, the street is lined with cafes and snackeries. Each advertises a different atmosphere. The high-class Starset, with individual tables, with waiters, mochas drawn in the shape of maidens, hot chocolate in tall glasses with swirly chocolate straws; the crowd-pleasing Delites, with bubble tea, self-serve yogurt machines with toppings, mochis in tantalizing rows beneath cartoon pictures of themselves, the color of their filling leaking through their faces like a soft blush. <!--more--> There’s simplitea, where you get a tea bag, hot water, and a place to sit for 50 cents. People go to Delites with a group of friends - no one will pay attention to you if you go alone - but somewhere like Serendipiteas, you are ushered in to a random seat, facing someone you do not know. In Melli’s Flows the conversations never stop, hurried on by the always-present bubbling fountain (careful: the fish bite), guests are encouraged to go from table to table, with different h’ors d’oveures at each table to tempt (free with entrance ticket).</p>
<p>There are tea houses to suit every taste - for the poor and the rich, for those who like talking about the weather (talking about the weather at Philosophocle is a very serious matter! For it is impossible to reduce the state of the weather to a word like “cloudy” or “sunny,” the emotions of the sky are more variegated than the emotions of people, being so much vaster in scope) to talking about ancient philosophy, world problems, or the most vulnerable yearning parts of one’s soul. (There’s one for quick romances as well, Impassioatta.) There’s the Unofficial Guide to Tea, released by the Students for Students Club at the University, but it’s not updated as often as the teahouses change managers, or compete to put up new menus, so it’s easy to fall out of date. Plus, there’s been a recent influx of art majors on the Committee, and they’ve decided to represent the major flavors of tea and coffee at the different teahouses with characters, which they give personalities - Green at The Leafy Bough is a gentleman in a suit, who will give you napkins before you ask for them, as opposed to Green at Melli’s, who is a smooth-talking man in a rainbow shirt whose hands are always moving, as opposed to Matcha at Delites, a plump little girl who will tell you all about the newest episodes of the current anime that’s sweeping those into Eastern culture.</p>
<p>There’s recently been a new addition. The Electric Eel, it’s called, and it looks like it’s been dropped here from another continent. It has an imported neon sign that flashes, its mascot eel alternating between blue and electric yellow. It’s taking a lot of business away from the other teahouses. It’s dark, they have fog machines, it serves iced tea rather than hot tea. If you ask me, they dilute the tea with too many ice cubes, but a lot of people seem to like clinking them around in their glasses. There’s a dance floor, with strips of light flowing around the walls. There’s some guy there who gives dance lessons, not the kind of ballroom dancing you do with a partner, but a dance you do individually. I hear that it’s amazing, people lined up in rows trying to copy the Great Danzini as they creak their joints in 360 degrees of movement and the “disco ball” alternately spotlights different amateur dancers. No one knows whether there’s one Danzini or three or ten, behind his mask - how can one man stay up dancing every night for so many hours? He never talks. He gets lots of tips.</p>
<p>I’m not so sure about the Electric Eel. Some of us think it’s a bad influence from the Continent, where such things are called “nightclubs” and are home to uncontrolled lewdness (Impassionatta, on the other hand, is quite controlled.). But we of course let the students have their fun, as long as they’re not violent.</p>

  </div>

    

    <!-- Extension : Sharing buttons @ www.sharethis.com -->
    <span class='st_facebook_large' displayText='Facebook'></span>
    <span class='st_twitter_large' displayText='Tweet'></span>
    <span class='st_googleplus_large' displayText='Google +'></span>
    <span class='st_reddit_large' displayText='Reddit'></span>
    <span class='st__large' displayText=''></span>

    <div id="disqus_thread"></div>
    


  
    <script>!function(d,s,id){var js,fjs=d.getElementsByTagName(s)[0],p=/^http:/.test(d.location)?'http':'https';if(!d.getElementById(id)){js=d.createElement(s);js.id=id;js.src=p+'://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js';fjs.parentNode.insertBefore(js,fjs);}}(document, 'script', 'twitter-wjs');</script>
  </div>
  
</div>
]]></summary>
</entry>

</feed>
