<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
    <title>Philosophocle</title>
    <link href="http://holdenlee.github.io/philosophocle/atom.xml" rel="self" />
    <link href="http://holdenlee.github.io/philosophocle" />
    <id>http://holdenlee.github.io/philosophocle/atom.xml</id>
    <author>
        <name>Scholars of Philosophocle</name>
        <email></email>
    </author>
    <updated>2016-05-15T00:00:00Z</updated>
    <entry>
    <title>Showdown</title>
    <link href="http://holdenlee.github.io/philosophocle/posts/showdown.html" />
    <id>http://holdenlee.github.io/philosophocle/posts/showdown.html</id>
    <published>2016-05-15T00:00:00Z</published>
    <updated>2016-05-15T00:00:00Z</updated>
    <summary type="html"><![CDATA[
<div class="container">
  <div id="content">
    <div class="page header">
      <h1>Showdown</h1>
    </div>
    <div class="info">
      
       
        <p class="subs">by Fron
	</p>
      
       
        <p class="subs">on 2016-05-15
	</p>
      
    </div>
    
  </div>
  <!--/div-->

  <hr>

  

  <div class="blog-main">
    <p>It has been more than a week since the showdown at the Scoop. The Scoop is still closed, and the Rhymist is still nowhere to be seen.</p>
<p>What happened? I will explain.</p>
<!--more-->
<h2 id="we-enter-the-scoop">1 We enter the Scoop</h2>
<p>At 8am last Tuesday, the Uniformists trooped into the Scoop. We each took a folding chair from the stack, unfolded it in front of the table, and sat down.<a href="#fn1" class="footnoteRef" id="fnref1"><sup>1</sup></a></p>
<p>We queued in front of the hot water machine. Each Uniformist took an identical cup from the counter, put in a bag of English Breakfast Tea, and then filled the cup with hot water. We each took one cookie (3cm in diameter, with 5 chocolate chips). We recognized one of our number behind the counter. He greeted us.</p>
<p>“How has your morning been?” he asked.</p>
<p>“Good. I woke up tired, but then remembered that today is the first Uniformist Day at the Scoop, and was heartened. I look forward to your cookies.”</p>
<p>Three other Scoopers sat behind the counter, watching us or reading The Philosophocler. Two of them also wore U-shirts. They looked slightly uncomfortable. They were not regulars (besides their shirts, they were non-uniform), but rather wore the shirts to make us feel welcome. We let them know our appreciation.</p>
<p>“Thank you for <a href="emergency-chaosing.html">making today Uniformist Day</a>,” we told them, “Thank you for the tea. You look good in that U-shirt. Please feel free to join us.”</p>
<p>The last Scooper wore a plain gray shirt, but the black U was absent, and the shirt was the wrong shade of gray. Her hair showed signs of having been dyed. (It’s not so easy to remove signs of Creativism.) She ignored our greetings.</p>
<p>“How are the cookies?” we asked each other.</p>
<p>“They are delicious. The texture is consistent.”</p>
<p>“How is the tea?”</p>
<p>“I have not tasted it yet, as it is hot. However, it smells fragrant.”</p>
<p>Un walked up to the chalkboard. It was empty—all the drawings of cartoon characters, improvisational poems, quotes urging readers to “go their own way” or “follow their hearts”, quadrilingual ramblings, and challenging mathematical equations having been erased by the Scoopers before we came. Un wrote in large letters, “WE ARE ALL HUMAN.”</p>
<p>We nodded.</p>
<p>“Well written.”</p>
<p>Finally we sat down.</p>
<h2 id="the-rhymist-arrives">2 The Rhymist arrives</h2>
<p>Before we started drinking our tea, however, we heard a cheerful creaking of floorboards, and found that a girl in red, holding a piece of bread (rather than a cookie), had joined us. In her other hand she held a mug, on which sat a ladybug.</p>
<p>“Heya,” she said, “I said I’d be back, to help you with what y’all lack.”</p>
<p>Un stood up. After the <a href="the-rhymist.html">disaster during Monday lunch</a>, he was prepared.</p>
<p>“Today is Uniformist day at the Scoop. You are welcome to join us if you wear a U-shirt and use the standard sentences from your complimentary copy of the Uniformist Guide to Conversation. Otherwise, we kindly request that you leave.”</p>
<p>She pulled up a stool (rather than a chair) beside Un and put her bug-mug down.</p>
<p>“You aren’t the only person who has a say,” she said, “I have a right to stay, unless everyone here votes nay.”</p>
<p>Un snatched the girl’s mug and took a sip. We looked at him in surprise.</p>
<p>“Aha! I know it!” Un said, “The Scoopers gave you cold tea!”</p>
<p>Being offered “cold tea” by the Scoopers is punishment for a severe breach of courtesy. It is a signal that one is no longer welcome at the Scoop.</p>
<p>In a smooth motion, the girl took Un’s cup and drank from it.</p>
<p>“As you took my brew, I presume your cup is now mine, while my mug belongs to you. This is strange, but I’ll agree to this exchange. But now you see, you are the one who has drunk cold tea, not me.”</p>
<p>Un’s face turned red.</p>
<p>He stood up, and thirty Uniformists pushed back their chairs and stood up. Alarmed, the girl in red took her slice of bread and Un’s cup, got up, and backed away.</p>
<p>We fanned out in a circle around her. Each one of us held a small U-shirt in our hands.</p>
<p>“Join us or leave,” Un said, moving towards her with the U-shirt held in front of him.</p>
<p>“Let me leave in peace,” she said, “I will depart to Deepsea Teas.”</p>
<h2 id="i-call-out-to-the-rhymist">3 I call out to the Rhymist</h2>
<p><em>Deepsea Teas</em>? That was the cafe with booths separated by fish tanks of deep-sea creatures.</p>
<p>Was she “jellyfish girl”?</p>
<p>The thought washed away my morning Uniformization.</p>
<p>I remembered how Lisa, the girl I had talked to so earnestly at lunch one day, had tricked me into thinking she had been the 3am announcer for <a href="PHSS.html">PHSS</a>, even though her voice was harsh rather than mellifluous, and she was dismissive, rather than appreciative, of life’s many mysteries. Thanks, however, to <a href="re-PHSS.html">Junali’s reporting</a> I had learned of her trickery from this very blog, and also learned that the radio announcer’s real name is Pearl.</p>
<p>Just as she reached the door, I broke the Uniformist ranks.</p>
<p>“Before you flee, beautiful girl, tell me—is your name Pearl?”</p>
<p>She stopped.</p>
<p>“That is a beautiful name—but it is not mine to claim.”</p>
<p>I did not lose hope. After all, Lisa could have lied in the blog post, to throw me off further! The rhyming girl had a quality of speech I have seen in few Philosophoclers. Many speak as if reading a memorized script, or with their tongues like automatic animals disjointed from their brains. Few speak as if they are following a beautiful road inside their head that only they can see.</p>
<p>“Grant me a wish—tell me, are you into jellyfish?”</p>
<p>“They are majestic creatures no doubt. But they’re full of stingers which can give you a lethal clout. I prefer animals less sadistic… and a little more pacifistic.”</p>
<p>My heart fell. But if I could just explain luminescent jellyfish to her…</p>
<p>“You! Get back here!” Un called.</p>
<p>So used was I to obeying the Uniformists that my feed started walking backwards. But I made myself stop.</p>
<p>“Let me tell you a memory I hold quite dear—this will explain my unexpected query. One night I turned on the radio and heard a voice extraordinary. With mellifluity and sibilence, a certain Pearl described the chemistry of of deep-sea luminescence—her voice was music, the quintessence. But soon it faded, like all beauty, evanescent. Since then I have journeyed far and wide, but never until you have I met someone so… rarefied. Speak that thread inside your head, and I will follow in your tread!”</p>
<p>A silence followed. Then, to my surprise, several other Uniformists stepped forward.</p>
<p>“What is your secret? I too want to have your spirit!”</p>
<p>“Tell me what to do, so I can rhyme as well as you!”</p>
<p>“The other Uniformists leer and sneer, but I will protect you, no fear!”</p>
<p>“Please don’t mind Fron, he’s a little obsessed. But with your presence, we are blessed!”</p>
<h2 id="a-suspicious-group-arrives">4 A suspicious group arrives</h2>
<p>Just then, the door opened. Fifteen people entered, all clad in U-shirts, and stood behind red-bread girl. However, the U-shirts all had a blue “2” next to the U, so that they read “U2”.</p>
<p>“How come you are U-shirted,” I asked, “But your shirts look strangely perverted?”</p>
<p>“That’s because we were tired of Uniformism—so we created a schism!”</p>
<p>“We’re not Uniformists—we’re Rhymists!”</p>
<p>“I didn’t know you had a group,” said one of the Uniformists, “can we too be part of the loop?”</p>
<p>“Yes, come with us to rhyme, and you’ll have a good time!”</p>
<p>“Please take a brochure; see all the benefits that you can procure!”</p>
<p>“Leave the Uniformist confines—we’ll give you some fresh new lines!”</p>
<p>“Rhyming is just the start—many more colorful ways to live we will impart!”</p>
<p>“Heart’s content! Time well spent! Things to invent! Leave behind torment. Ascent!”</p>
<p>Several of the Uniformists started to walk away with the “Rhymists.”</p>
<p>Then I saw two faces among the group that I realized. “Wait! Don’t take the bait! These people are not so great. They are Creativists!”</p>
<p>I pointed at Lukko. “My former roommate, who <a href="housing-optimization.html">I have come to hate</a>. Monstrous things he does create, which he uses to intimidate and infuriate!”</p>
<p>I pointed at Lisa. “And that is Lisa who one day <a href="re-PHSS.html">pretended to be</a> the jellyfish girl who so captured my heart. But she was playing a dirty trick on me, feeding me lies for the sake of art!”</p>
<p>My fellow Uniformists backed me up.</p>
<p>“You’re not a Rhymist. You’re a two-timist!”</p>
<p>(One of the Creativists spoke up, “Lukko and Lisa, is that true? This isn’t what Creativists supposed to do!”)</p>
<p>“We won’t join you!” another Uni yelled.</p>
<p>We back away from the Creativists.</p>
<p>“What’s up! Argh, I mean, what a fuckup! I should have put on some makeup!” Lisa said.</p>
<p>“Well, now that our cover is gone, we might as well have some fun!”</p>
<p>Lukko took off his U2-shirt, which had been covering <a href="housing-optimization.html">my monstrosity</a>. All the other Creativists followed suit, and we were accosted by an explosion of color, glitter, glitter glue, metal hooks, plastic eyes, pipe cleaners, bubble-letters, random quotes, beads, buttons, paint, felt, sew-on-pockets, cardboard, cotton balls, flower petals, acorn caps, last autumn’s leaves, feathers dropped from birds in flight, and coconut shells.</p>
<p>Lukko unpacked several canisters of paint from his bag.</p>
<p>“If they won’t become Creativists of their own free will, then colors must spill!”</p>
<h2 id="hell-breaks-loose">5 Hell breaks loose</h2>
<p>Creativists scooped up handfuls of color and charged us. They ran up to Uniformists and dabbed the colors onto Uniformist faces, hair, necks, and shirts. Uniformists with rainbow-colored faces chased after the Creativists, who defended themselves with drumsticks and tambourines. Chairs overturned. Hot tea sloshed through the air.</p>
<p>One of the Scoopers was busy shooting photographs—photographs which would appear in the Wednesday issue of The Philosophocler. Another Scooper—the one with the fake gray shirt—had taken rainbow-colored cookies out of the oven, climbed over the counter, and dunked her hair in paint with the desperation of a thirsty baboon.</p>
<p>I quickly hid below a table, and found that I had been joined by several Uniformists and Creativists, as well as the single true Rhymist.</p>
<p>“This is causing me a lot of stress. Can you tell your Creativists to stop this mess?” said a boy I later learned was Timoo.</p>
<p>“Stop! War is destructive, not creative!” said the girl holding his hand, who I later learned was Rudii.</p>
<p>No one listened.</p>
<p>“I wanted everyone to have fun with rhyme,” the Rhymist said sadly, shaking her head. “But all I did was cause tons of crime.”</p>
<p>“It’s not your fault,” I said. “Campus security will come, and charge the guilty with assault.”</p>
<p>I looked around at the people—Uniformists and Creativists alike—gathered under the table.</p>
<p>“Let them fight their petty rivalry,” I said, “We’ll start our own philosophy. Will you lead us, oh rhyming princess—after, of course, we make our egress?”</p>
<p>The Rhymist put down her cup and bread, and smoothed her shirt of red. She stood up and walked forwards.</p>
<p>“That’s the wrong way!” Rudii yelled. “That’s into the fray!”</p>
<p>“I must remedy what I started,” she said in a faraway voice, “For Moses, the waters have parted.” She walked into the melee.</p>
<p>We lost sight of her.</p>
<p><strong>“I come in the name of peace. Let all hostilities cease!”</strong></p>
<p>“Shut your beaks, the Rhymist speaks!”</p>
<p>“The Rhymist is a two-timist!”</p>
<p><strong>“Stop fighting head to head, let’s play a word game instead!”</strong></p>
<p>“Watch where you’re throwing that color!”</p>
<p>“Don’t holler!”</p>
<p>“Everyone, stop! An unarmed Rhymist’s in our midst, we must desist!”</p>
<p>Uniformists and Creativists stopped. Raised fists were dropped.</p>
<p>We breathed a sigh of relief.</p>
<p>“Where is the Rhymist? <em>Where is the Rhymist</em>?”</p>
<p>“Rhymist, we have stopped. Please speak to us!”</p>
<p>We strained our ears, but did not hear a single line. The only remnant of the Rhymist was the cup and bread she had left with us under the table.</p>
<p>The door burst open. Campus security had arrived. “Everyone out,” a policeman said. “The Scoop is now closed.”</p>
<section class="footnotes">
<hr />
<ol>
<li id="fn1"><p>The usual Scoop chairs are one-of-a-kind and unreliable, as they were either made by Creativist artisans, or purchased or otherwise acquired on whim by Creativist-aligned Scoopers. The folding chairs, on the other hand, are made in bulk by an unassuming company called Chair Makers. Even for inanimate objects, uniformism is correlated with goodness. (Footnote by Un.)<a href="#fnref1">↩</a></p></li>
</ol>
</section>

  </div>

    

    <!-- Previous/next post-->
    <div>
    
    <a href="/posts/the-rhymist.html" style="float:left;">Previous post</a>
    
    
    </div>
    <br>

    <!-- Extension : Sharing buttons @ www.sharethis.com -->
    <span class='st_facebook_large' displayText='Facebook'></span>
    <span class='st_twitter_large' displayText='Tweet'></span>
    <span class='st_googleplus_large' displayText='Google +'></span>
    <span class='st_reddit_large' displayText='Reddit'></span>
    <span class='st__large' displayText=''></span>

    <div id="disqus_thread"></div>
    


  
    <script>!function(d,s,id){var js,fjs=d.getElementsByTagName(s)[0],p=/^http:/.test(d.location)?'http':'https';if(!d.getElementById(id)){js=d.createElement(s);js.id=id;js.src=p+'://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js';fjs.parentNode.insertBefore(js,fjs);}}(document, 'script', 'twitter-wjs');</script>
  </div>
  
</div>
]]></summary>
</entry>
<entry>
    <title>The Rhymist</title>
    <link href="http://holdenlee.github.io/philosophocle/posts/the-rhymist.html" />
    <id>http://holdenlee.github.io/philosophocle/posts/the-rhymist.html</id>
    <published>2016-05-03T00:00:00Z</published>
    <updated>2016-05-03T00:00:00Z</updated>
    <summary type="html"><![CDATA[
<div class="container">
  <div id="content">
    <div class="page header">
      <h1>The Rhymist</h1>
    </div>
    <div class="info">
      
       
        <p class="subs">by Fron
	</p>
      
       
        <p class="subs">on 2016-05-03
	</p>
      
    </div>
    
  </div>
  <!--/div-->

  <hr>

  

  <div class="blog-main">
    <p>(Monday)</p>
<p>There is a seat missing among us today. One of the regular Unis is sick and cannot come.</p>
<p>A petite girl with a large book of <em>Classical Ballads</em> sits down in the empty chair. She has a taco salad. None of us got a taco salad, because unlike all the other entrees which are eaten with spoon and fork, it is too hands-on. Eating a taco salad would distinguish us from others. She has a side of curried cauliflower, rather than the peppered peas that the rest of us have. She is wearing a blue shirt, not a U-shirt.</p>
<p>We all look at her, unsure how to respond. I wait for another to speak up, but of course, we are all waiting for another to speak up, so none of us do.</p>
<p>“Heya,” she says brightly. “On the surface you look the same/ Makes me wonder what are y’all’s names?”</p>
<!--more-->
<p>She puts down <em>Classical Ballads</em>, and proceeds to crunch into her taco salad.</p>
<p>“Our names aren’t important,” I pipe up, and am not surprised to see two others say the exact same sentence at the exact same time, “As humans, we are all quite interchangeable.”</p>
<p>“I think you’ll find that’s just not true,” she said, “come test time, if you sit in lieu/ of someone else, that’d be quite an oopsy-doo!”</p>
<p>“Stop it,” one of the Unis piped up, “Are you aware what you’re saying is quite taboo?”</p>
<p>“John, don’t rhyme with her, that’ll only encourage the cur,” another pipes up, then colors, realizing he has said John’s name out loud, which is, in fact, quite taboo.</p>
<p>“Are you a Creativist?” another Uni demands. “You’re not welcome at our <a href="uniformist-lunch-table.html">table</a>!”</p>
<p>“It makes me sad to see a group that’s so unstable/ when someone new comes sitting down, she’s quickly slapped an enemy’s label!”</p>
<p>A Uniformist clangs his spoon on the dish. “I must insist that you desist, at this table not a single Creativist is allowed to exist!”</p>
<p>“Everyone, please stop talking,” Un says, “Be calm, I’ll go report this act of stalking.”</p>
<p>Our chewing has gotten out of sync. Panicking Unis are eating their foods out of order—some of us have finished all our peas before our soup, while others have finished our soup before our peas. One of us has dumped peas into his soup. Some of us find our mouths moving without food, as if sounding out silent words. Rather than looking at each other, as Uniformists should, we are all looking at her.</p>
<p>“I am quite curious, if you all eat and dress the same, does that make you spurious?”</p>
<p>“I don’t appreciate your mind game,” one Uniformist growled.</p>
<p>“I am not playing with you,” said salad-ballad girl in blue. “I am merely saying what’s true.”</p>
<p>“Let me explain,” I break in. “Though plain, our lives need no supplement. We are content.”</p>
<p>She looks at me. “You pretend to hide behind an unremarkable life, but really you’re hiding from your internal strife.”</p>
<p>The girl is making sounds with her mouth. She puffs up her cheeks and expels air repeatedly. She snaps her fingers with her non-taco holding hand. We look at her and at each other in confusion: is this some derisory Creativist gesture? The blasts of air and regular snaps, however, draw us in. Listening to it, we again find a rhythm with our chewing. Various Unis speak up.</p>
<p>“You have no place within our bunch. Please let us eat our lunch.”</p>
<p>“You do not belong here. I think this is clear.”</p>
<p>“Your values do not mesh with ours. Leave, before this whole thing sours.”</p>
<p>“Stop!” I say. “Is this the Uniformist way? What merits such a rude display?”</p>
<p>“Fron, she’s turning us into Creativists! We’ve completely deviated from the usual scripts! We’re coming up with new rhymes every time we open our mouth to speak, so everyone, shut your mouths and turn the other cheek!”</p>
<p>I realize that indeed, she is keeping a beat. Our syllables are falling right into her beats, one-to-one, in a way reminiscent of how the Philosophocle Rights and Responsibilities booklet fall into our mailboxes at the beginning of each semester. Unis are drumming on the tables with their fingers, spooning peas every other beat, and opening and closing their mouths like fish.</p>
<p>A Uniformist stands up. We all stare at him. By standing up he has distinguished himself.</p>
<p>“Get out! Or I’ll—I’ll… give you a big clout!”</p>
<p>The girl abruptly stops crunching her taco salad and looks at the offender, who is making threatening arm movements in her direction.</p>
<p>“From your brochure I read that I’d be treated with civility. But since I’ve come I’ve been met with nothing but hostility. Therefore I will now be off, leave behind the halls of lunchtime’s dreary coughs. You can stay and repeat another day—or you can follow the river of what can be said, the song inside your head.”</p>
<p>With this she gets up and starts to leave. She takes her <em>Classical Ballads</em> and taco salad in her hands, leaving her tray behind.</p>
<p>Chairs scrape up as several Uniformists abandon their food, “Please don’t leave without me, I too want to be free!” One Uniformist is busy taking off his U-shirt.</p>
<p>My heart pounds. Should I follow them?</p>
<p>She doesn’t look back. “I do not like what I see. But I am not deaf to your plea. If you want another opportunity, meet me at the Scoop for tea.”</p>
<p>And then she is gone.</p>
<p>“You, you, you!” Un says to the Uniformists who had stood up. “Sit down!”</p>
<p>“I’m sorry. I—I—I didn’t know what came over me,” says the boy who had taken off his U-shirt. He hurriedly put it back on.</p>
<p>“Un, we must not go to the Scoop tomorrow,” someone says. “I don’t know what kind of demonic powers that girl has.”</p>
<p>“We certainly <em>will</em> meet her tomorrow for tea,” Un said, his face dark with rage and his fists clenched.</p>
<p>Un had fought tirelessly for <a href="emergency-chaosing.html">“Uniformist Day” at the Scoop</a>. He had written letters to the Director of Religious Life, the Student Activities Board, the Student Judicial Board, the Board Against Discrimination and For Tolerance, and even appealed to the President. Nothing is going to keep him from his rightful place at the Scoop tomorrow.</p>
<p>“<em>All of us</em>. We will teach her that <em>no one</em> messes with the Uniformists. When we are done with her, I promise you, she will be a Uniformist.”</p>
<p>Un sits back in his chair and takes a deep breath to calm himself down. Nods spread around the table.</p>
<p>“Sit down, everyone. Take a breath, in… out… Straighten your backs. Open your books to page ten.”</p>
<p>We take out our pocket-sized Guides to Uniformisms. All of us—even the ones who had previously protested—read page ten<a href="#fn1" class="footnoteRef" id="fnref1"><sup>1</sup></a> out loud. But I cannot return to that previous zen. The girl’s poetry was a unique kind of song. For the first time, I’m not sure that I really belong.</p>
<p>As we read the Uniformization, I don’t process the words at all. They are dull and dreary. I feel I am going through a bleary pantomime. I can’t help but imagine what will happen if every sentence were replaced by rhyme.</p>
<p>There is something beautiful about salad-ballad girl, which none of the other Uniformists understand. Something momentuous, I know, will happen tomorrow. I do not know what, but I know that I cannot allow Un to turn her into a Uniformist.</p>
<section class="footnotes">
<hr />
<ol>
<li id="fn1"><p>The Uniformization, which helps us return to a uniform state after we have been disturbed.<a href="#fnref1">↩</a></p></li>
</ol>
</section>

  </div>

    

    <!-- Previous/next post-->
    <div>
    
    <a href="/posts/agnostic-2.html" style="float:left;">Previous post</a>
    
    
    <a href="/posts/showdown.html" style="float:right; text-align: right;">Next post</a>
    
    </div>
    <br>

    <!-- Extension : Sharing buttons @ www.sharethis.com -->
    <span class='st_facebook_large' displayText='Facebook'></span>
    <span class='st_twitter_large' displayText='Tweet'></span>
    <span class='st_googleplus_large' displayText='Google +'></span>
    <span class='st_reddit_large' displayText='Reddit'></span>
    <span class='st__large' displayText=''></span>

    <div id="disqus_thread"></div>
    


  
    <script>!function(d,s,id){var js,fjs=d.getElementsByTagName(s)[0],p=/^http:/.test(d.location)?'http':'https';if(!d.getElementById(id)){js=d.createElement(s);js.id=id;js.src=p+'://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js';fjs.parentNode.insertBefore(js,fjs);}}(document, 'script', 'twitter-wjs');</script>
  </div>
  
</div>
]]></summary>
</entry>
<entry>
    <title>A neutral viewpoint on Creativism and Uniformism</title>
    <link href="http://holdenlee.github.io/philosophocle/posts/agnostic-2.html" />
    <id>http://holdenlee.github.io/philosophocle/posts/agnostic-2.html</id>
    <published>2016-04-30T00:00:00Z</published>
    <updated>2016-04-30T00:00:00Z</updated>
    <summary type="html"><![CDATA[
<div class="container">
  <div id="content">
    <div class="page header">
      <h1>A neutral viewpoint on Creativism and Uniformism</h1>
    </div>
    <div class="info">
      
       
        <p class="subs">by Agnes
	</p>
      
       
        <p class="subs">on 2016-04-30
	</p>
      
    </div>
    
  </div>
  <!--/div-->

  <hr>

  

  <div class="blog-main">
    <p>It seems like more and more students are converting to either Uniformism or Creativism every day. Much of this can be attributed to <a href="/posts/how-i-became-a-creativist.html">Trevisia</a>’s and <a href="/posts/how-i-became-a-uniformist.html">Fron</a>’s recent fiery posts. Many come to my office during walk-in hours to ask whether they are more suited for Uniformism or Creativism. “If you have to ask,” I tell them, “Perhaps you are <a href="/posts/agnostic.html">neither</a>.”</p>
<!--more-->
<p>During this stressful time of year, with thesis deadlines and final exams coming up, students seek a support group. It is not surprising that the Uniformists have swelled in rank: joining requires only a purchase of a shirt and instantly allows the wearer to join the Uniformist group of friends at lunch (especially appealing if one has no friends). Joining the Creativists, on the other hand, requires a heroic effort; although they call it an Initiation, the term “hazing” is more accurate<a href="#fn1" class="footnoteRef" id="fnref1"><sup>1</sup></a>; furthermore their meetings are more chaotic then friendly, involving spilled paint, broken voices, collapsing chairs, and rap battles. Recently, however, they are debating whether to allow members to join for a two-month trial period before Initiation. This is a step in the right direction.</p>
<p>Some readers have questioned my neutral status. Is my post on <a href="running.html">running</a> not a insult to the Uniformists? No, I merely tell the truth as it is. As you can see from this post, I am equally critical to the Creativists and the Uniformists.</p>
<p>Recently, after a lengthy process, the Scoop, traditionally a very Creativist enterprise, has declared that <a href="emergency-chaosing.html">Tuesdays will be Uniformist day</a>. I am pleased with the decision; however, many are not. I am sure that already, the Creativists are planning retaliation. I urged Trevisia not to give in to intolerance, but she merely made a creative face at me and hurried on her way.</p>
<p>I am worried. It is only a matter of time before the Uniformists and Creativists will come to blows again.</p>
<section class="footnotes">
<hr />
<ol>
<li id="fn1"><p>Our foreign friends will be familiar with this word, but for those who have never ventured abroad, let me explain. In foreign universities, students belong to “fraternities” and “sororities,” which are the analogue of our religions except that they are devoid of ideology. Fraternities and sororities are characterized by a “hazing” process which involves running in the streets naked, drinking copious amounts of alcohol, navigating booby-trapped mazes while blindfolded, being pushed backwards into a lake, and so forth. While the specific activities are different, their essence is similar; the key difference between fraternists and Creativists is that for Creativists, these types of activities are self-inflicted.<a href="#fnref1">↩</a></p></li>
</ol>
</section>

  </div>

    

    <!-- Previous/next post-->
    <div>
    
    <a href="/posts/emergency-chaosing.html" style="float:left;">Previous post</a>
    
    
    <a href="/posts/the-rhymist.html" style="float:right; text-align: right;">Next post</a>
    
    </div>
    <br>

    <!-- Extension : Sharing buttons @ www.sharethis.com -->
    <span class='st_facebook_large' displayText='Facebook'></span>
    <span class='st_twitter_large' displayText='Tweet'></span>
    <span class='st_googleplus_large' displayText='Google +'></span>
    <span class='st_reddit_large' displayText='Reddit'></span>
    <span class='st__large' displayText=''></span>

    <div id="disqus_thread"></div>
    


  
    <script>!function(d,s,id){var js,fjs=d.getElementsByTagName(s)[0],p=/^http:/.test(d.location)?'http':'https';if(!d.getElementById(id)){js=d.createElement(s);js.id=id;js.src=p+'://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js';fjs.parentNode.insertBefore(js,fjs);}}(document, 'script', 'twitter-wjs');</script>
  </div>
  
</div>
]]></summary>
</entry>
<entry>
    <title>Emergency Chaosing</title>
    <link href="http://holdenlee.github.io/philosophocle/posts/emergency-chaosing.html" />
    <id>http://holdenlee.github.io/philosophocle/posts/emergency-chaosing.html</id>
    <published>2016-04-28T00:00:00Z</published>
    <updated>2016-04-28T00:00:00Z</updated>
    <summary type="html"><![CDATA[
<div class="container">
  <div id="content">
    <div class="page header">
      <h1>Emergency Chaosing</h1>
    </div>
    <div class="info">
      
       
        <p class="subs">by Trevisia
	</p>
      
       
        <p class="subs">on 2016-04-28
	</p>
      
    </div>
    
  </div>
  <!--/div-->

  <hr>

  

  <div class="blog-main">
    <p>At the emergency chaosing, Rudii announced to everyone the news I had given her: starting next week, every Tuesday would be Uniformist Day at the <a href="/posts/the-scoop.html">Scoop</a>.</p>
<!--more-->
<p>“How could you have let this happen, Trevisia?” Rudii asked.</p>
<p>She sat on the grass, <a href="creativist-love.html">Timoo</a> by her side. Timoo was busy looking at all the Creativists and smiling, taking us all in one by one. Ah, to be as carefree as Timoo, seeing Creativism for the first time!</p>
<p>“I was outvoted. Every few days I suggest to the other Scoopers that we should be an anarchy. They don’t listen! The Scoop management remains a democracy.”</p>
<p>“How bad is the Uniformist takeover?”</p>
<p>“On Tuesday morning, the Scoopers will erase the board. They will replace the paint-your-own-mugs by forty Uniformist mugs, each gray with a black U, and only offer English Breakfast Tea—no jasmine green, cranberry hibiscus, ginger chili spice, oolong, or rooibos. The Uniformist who has just been trained in cookie-baking—he wouldn’t deign to tell us his name, so I will call him Unfun—will supervise the baking, and make sure each cookie has exactly five chocolate chips and is three inches in diameter. ‘Different sized cookies are unfair and cause stress,’ he says. The Uniformists will come in a horde, because where there’s one Uniformist there’s always thirty.”</p>
<p>The Creativists reacted each in their own way: shuddering, grimacing, clawing at her cheeks, falling off a chair, scratching nails against a portable blackboard, covering his eyes, unsheathing a cardboard sword, or screaming.</p>
<p>“But the Scoop is open to all,” Numms said, “We can all still come. We’ll sit at a separate table. We’ll bring our own mugs that we painted.”</p>
<p>“But Numms, the Scoopers will give ‘cold tea’ to anyone who breaks the Uniformist atmosphere. For our whole club to get ‘cold tea’…”</p>
<p>“Cold tea isn’t bad. Why’s everyone shitting on cold tea?”</p>
<p>“Not all of us prefer ‘cold tea’, Lisa.”</p>
<p>“We should have taken over the Scoop long ago! Then we wouldn’t have to worry about the Scoopers betraying us!” shouted Lukko.</p>
<p>“Would it really be that bad? We can just stay away; we can still get our cookies the other six days of the week…”</p>
<p>“But we’d have to stay away from the Workshop, too. Would you feel comfy in the Workshop if thirty Unifomists do their ‘formal tea chant’ above your head?”</p>
<p>“We’ll sing our own songs! I’ll teach you all a song right now, it’s called ‘The song which never repeats a single word’.”</p>
<p>“Or we can wear earmuffs. Come join my impromptu earmuff-making spree!” Cotton balls of all colors spilled out onto the table.</p>
<p>“We’ll wear U-shirts and sneak in. They won’t be able to tell, because they can’t distinguish anyone who’s wearing a U-shirt. Then when we sit at their table, we’ll take off our shirts!”</p>
<p>“WHAT??? We’re not Sexists!”</p>
<p>“I meant, we would have on Creativist shirts underneath.”</p>
<p>“We’ll sit at their table and do this!” I took out several canisters of paint and spilled them all over the picnic table.</p>
<p>“My cotton balls!”</p>
<p>Rainbow paintfalls globbed over the edge of the table, carrying the balls with them. It was truly an impromptu piece of art. It was a shame our photographer was not here.</p>
<p>“Trevisia, this is an unacceptable waste of paint,” Rudii said severely. “As punishment you are not to touch any paint, dyes, markers, colored pencils, food coloring, or tomato juice over the next week.”</p>
<p>No color? I suppressed my horror, and tried to get back into Rudii’s good graces.</p>
<p>“I have another idea! We’ll bake thirty-seven different kinds of cookies. We can’t use the Scoop ovens, but I know the locations of many ovens on campus. When they eat the cookies, we’ll have planted the seeds of Creativism in their stomach.”</p>
<p>Rudii had gone, though. My idea floated in the air, unheard.</p>
<p>I looked around and saw that everyone was busy suggesting ideas—through dialogue, song, mimes, or interpretive dance—and no one was listening. Several Creativists were engaged in fights with sticks, with Numms pretending to a Uniformist reciting the statement of the Law of Large Numbers. The only person paying me any attention was Timoo, who was catching the paint globbing off the table with his shirt.</p>
<p>“Paint is bad for grass,” he said.</p>
<p><em>Glop, glop, glop.</em></p>
<p>“Thanks,” I said. “I’m sorry. I just got over-excited, and thought the world needed more color.”</p>
<p>Timoo gestured at the rest of the group. “Is it always like this?”</p>
<p>I nodded. “There’s a reason we call our meetings ‘chaosings’. We’re not very good at—”</p>
<p>“Order,” Rudii was saying, “To order! Please come together. We must agree on a common plan.”</p>
<p>But no one paid attention.</p>
<!--Rudii soon gave up, and instead started to do improvisational tai chi to calm her nerves. Unfortunately, this made her all the more ignorable.-->
<hr>
<p>Until…</p>
<p>From somewhere unseen, she came like an answer from a god.</p>
<p>Wearing a shirt of green, reminiscent of a pea-pod.</p>
<p>In her hand she held a single bean.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>“Heya, it’s nice to stumble upon a group so varied, but pray tell: what has you so harried?”</p>
</blockquote>
<!--I wonder how y'all do; looking around I see a veritable stew!-->
<!-- "I can't help but hear your troubled tone, I came over to ask: what do you bemoan?"-->
<p>Everyone stopped what they were doing at looked at the bold girl.</p>
<p>“Hostile takeover! Loss of creativity! Erasure!” Chyme said as she acted out her words.</p>
<!--CHANGE TO SOMETHING NEW-->
<p>I stepped in front of Chyme before she could talk more. “Do you walk through campus along the same path every day? Do you despair upon seeing architecture made of identical bricks and identical columns? Then Creativism might be for you. We believe in taking a different path every day. We believe that every person and every thing should be different, like snowflakes, except much more so.”</p>
<p>I threw her a plain white shirt from my bag.</p>
<p>“As a warm-up you can design your own T-shirt. Make sure it is sufficiently different from every shirt you’ve seen! Please come back only when you have finished! Then I’ll explain the <a href="how-i-became-a-creativist-ii.html">Initiation</a> to you.” As always, I had several new wooden boxes that I had ready in my pocket.</p>
<p>The girl smiled.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>“I thank you kindly for that quick debrief—it’s good to hear a statement of belief. But please give me the honor, rainbow chief. I’d like to help you assuage your grief.”</p>
</blockquote>
<p>“What grief? We’re all happy here with our creative lives.”</p>
<blockquote>
<p>“I thought I heard some screaming. Not at all like happy dreaming. Not all is what it’s seeming, so I ask you for the meaning.”</p>
</blockquote>
<p>“Thank you for your greeting,” I insisted, “But we’re in the middle of a private meeting.”</p>
<p>“Strangers in our midst we’ll have to baptize,” Lukko said, “For what if you’re a Uniformist in disguise? I know they’re trying to infiltrate us with spies!”</p>
<p>The girl in green closed her hand around her bean, and took up a somber mien.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>“Forgive me, but I’m not sure I want to join so soon. I take things slowly, like the waxing of the moon. I thought y’all had a friendly vibe, but I guess you’re just another campus tribe.”</p>
</blockquote>
<p>“Creativists!” Rudii said firmly. “This is no way to treat a guest! We’ve got to show this girl our best. Just like Timoo here, you’re not going to tell him shoo, are you?” She looked pointedly at us, before turning back to green-bean girl.</p>
<p>“Do you know about the Uniformists?”</p>
<blockquote>
<p>“Are they the ones with shirts of gray? I’ve only seen them from far away. In groups they make an imposing display!”</p>
</blockquote>
<p>“It’s right to be on your toes,” Rudii said, “You don’t want to get too close. Right now they’re trying to take over the Scoop. We can’t let them come and—and—” she stumbled, looking confused.</p>
<p>“—leave behind their poop,” Lisa finished. Her eyes widened. “Oh, shit! You’re doing it!”</p>
<p>“What?”</p>
<p>“You’re talking in rhyme! Didn’t you have trouble for the longest time?”</p>
<p>Rudii looked at green-bean girl in wonder. “What manner of creature are you?”</p>
<blockquote>
<p>“I am someone quite true. But I did not come to talk about me, I came in pursuit of harmony. I’m tired of all this name-calling; I have in mind something much more enthralling.</p>
<p>“What works for Creativists works for Uniformists. The plan is this: I sit among them, and they’ll ask me ‘Have you lost your way, miss?’ or cough loudly, <em>ahem</em>. I’ll start speaking in rhyme. For many, it’ll be their first time. My words will seem like magic, and they’ll feel their lack of creativism as quite tragic.”</p>
</blockquote>
<!--But I did not come so you'd be impressed by me. I come in the service of harmony.-->
<p>“Forgive me for my skepticism,” I said, “But you’re going to convert Uniformists into Creativism?” I asked.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>“You can’t deny the power of rhyme. It orders your thoughts over the course of time. Takes thoughts weighted down by daily grime, and cleanses them until they’re shining sublime.”</p>
</blockquote>
<p>FizzleGo, the performance poet, was seething with disapproval. He couldn’t help but finally show it.</p>
<p>“Rhyming isn’t the same as Creativism! It’s more like… hypnotism! Anyone can rhyme a syllable—true poetry is much more unpredictable. Rhyming is lazy, it encourages our thoughts to be hazy. Rather than putting your ideas in accord, all you have to do is end with the right word. Aargh! Bargh!”</p>
<p>Rudii agreed. “Just because you teach them to rhyme, doesn’t mean they’ll pick up the creative paradigm.”</p>
<p>Lukko spoke up. “I know, you’ll be the bait—you’ll hold them stupefied. In that malleable state, we’ll teach them to create—until they’re completely transmogrified!”</p>
<p>We looked back at green-bean girl—or where she had been. Now she was nowhere to be seen.</p>
<p>Gone as quickly as she had come. Mysteriously, like a garden gnome.</p>
<p>“She’s gone! We shouldn’t have scared her with our tone.”</p>
<p>“By jove! We didn’t show her enough love.”</p>
<p>“You all sound weirdly dissonant,” Rudii said, “You were rhyming but now you… can’t.”</p>
<!--CHANGE: She disappears. Then they fail to rhyme?-->
<!--We talked for a long time more, but the details will have to wait until afer the war. Uniformist eyes are everywhere---and they must remain unaware.-->

  </div>

    

    <!-- Previous/next post-->
    <div>
    
    <a href="/posts/creativist-love.html" style="float:left;">Previous post</a>
    
    
    <a href="/posts/agnostic-2.html" style="float:right; text-align: right;">Next post</a>
    
    </div>
    <br>

    <!-- Extension : Sharing buttons @ www.sharethis.com -->
    <span class='st_facebook_large' displayText='Facebook'></span>
    <span class='st_twitter_large' displayText='Tweet'></span>
    <span class='st_googleplus_large' displayText='Google +'></span>
    <span class='st_reddit_large' displayText='Reddit'></span>
    <span class='st__large' displayText=''></span>

    <div id="disqus_thread"></div>
    


  
    <script>!function(d,s,id){var js,fjs=d.getElementsByTagName(s)[0],p=/^http:/.test(d.location)?'http':'https';if(!d.getElementById(id)){js=d.createElement(s);js.id=id;js.src=p+'://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js';fjs.parentNode.insertBefore(js,fjs);}}(document, 'script', 'twitter-wjs');</script>
  </div>
  
</div>
]]></summary>
</entry>
<entry>
    <title>Creativist love</title>
    <link href="http://holdenlee.github.io/philosophocle/posts/creativist-love.html" />
    <id>http://holdenlee.github.io/philosophocle/posts/creativist-love.html</id>
    <published>2016-04-23T00:00:00Z</published>
    <updated>2016-04-23T00:00:00Z</updated>
    <summary type="html"><![CDATA[
<div class="container">
  <div id="content">
    <div class="page header">
      <h1>Creativist love</h1>
    </div>
    <div class="info">
      
       
        <p class="subs">by Trevisia
	</p>
      
       
        <p class="subs">on 2016-04-23
	</p>
      
    </div>
    
  </div>
  <!--/div-->

  <hr>

  

  <div class="blog-main">
    <p>I’m so happy for Rudii—she has finally fallen in love at first sight! Or as we like to say, “instant concoction”!<a href="#fn1" class="footnoteRef" id="fnref1"><sup>1</sup></a></p>
<p>You might say it’s just coincidence. But actually, being a Creativist gives you a higher chance of falling in love! Let’s start with some history.</p>
<!--more-->
<h2 id="a-historical-revelation">A Historical Revelation</h2>
<p>One evening Albern called together a communal chaosing<a href="#fn2" class="footnoteRef" id="fnref2"><sup>2</sup></a> at the Scoop to discuss a passage of utmost importance he’d found in an yearbook so old its pages were yellowed and brittle.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>Yesterday night I felt despondent in the Workshop as I gazed at the last few cotton balls, colored pencil stubs, and holey socks in our possession. If only I were a fairy, so I would weave something from the rich, magical, but immaterial moonlight shining through the window!</p>
<p>“I might have to fashion something out of cobwebs,” I said to Spyzer, to which he replied solemnly, “Taking someone’s home like that would be rather Destructivist.”</p>
<p>It was only a joke. But I couldn’t help but wonder, <em>Why am I a Creativist?</em> I knew the answer: I revel in that secret joy of making things—the feeling of taking paths never before traveled. When I finish a new sculpture, I rush to show my friends, but they misinterpret it (“is it… an abstract idea?”); they cannot truly understand, for they have not walked through the path that has only be traveled by me. Surely we are not Creativists because we want to walk alone. Is the path of Creativism fundamentally a path of solitude?</p>
<p>This morning I have found an answer. I had a revelation that came to me through a dream. In this dream I was standing on behind a long table of Uniformists.</p>
<p>“I love you with all my heart,” said a boy to a girl. They looked almost identical except for the angle of their cheekbones and the length of their hair. They were both clad in U-shirts.</p>
<p>“Do not love just one, we are all the same,” she said, hopelessly, “If you love one, then you must love all.”</p>
<p>I’ve never been at a Uniformist lunch table, but my dream told me this was the standard Uniformist answer. I also knew that she didn’t believe it. She struggled to find the next words, because the standard answer ended there.</p>
<p>She continued, unexpectedly, but in a whisper. “That might be nice, thought, to love someone with all my heart. But you, and… you and you, how can I decide, when you seem so similar?”</p>
<p>“Dedication. We are all the same, but some of us are more dedicated than the others. Name the contest, madam.” This was also a standard Uniformist response.</p>
<p>I imagined the boys, stringing identical bows aiming at identical targets, or hunched over identical crossword puzzles or logic conundrums, or running along an identical path up the hill. Their eyes, however, were all clouded. They had no love. They were nothing but machines of Uniformist dedication.</p>
</blockquote>
<p>“What’s the revelation?”</p>
<p>“It ends there,” Albern said.</p>
<p>“When is it from? Who wrote it?”</p>
<p>“I don’t know. The cover says ‘Year of the Doughy Pineapples’.”<a href="#fn3" class="footnoteRef" id="fnref3"><sup>3</sup></a></p>
<p>“For all we know, it’s a joke, written by someone yesterday and dipped in paper-yellowing chemicals! Probably she was too lazy to come up with a proper revelation, and she’ll be laughing her ass off shortly,” Lisa looked around, but no one was laughing, “Remember the entries that were written by a ‘superintelligent monkey’?<a href="#fn4" class="footnoteRef" id="fnref4"><sup>4</sup></a>”</p>
<p>“Perhaps the writer was strangled by a Uniformist before ey could finish.”</p>
<p>Rudii raised her hand for attention. “It doesn’t whether the entry was created from real or fictional experience. What matters is the content. Does Creativism helps concoction?”</p>
<p>“It’s <em>obvious</em> that we would do much better in love than Uniformists,” Lukko said.</p>
<p>“I consulted Dave,” Albern replied. “Based on surveys, there is no statistically significant difference in romantic success for Creativists or Uniformists. There is, however, a significant difference between us and the Romanticists, who do better.”</p>
<p>“It’s all in their heads!” Lukko objected.</p>
<p>Romanticists tended to like dreaming more than actual creating.</p>
<p>“Probably the Creativists just gave creative answers that Dave couldn’t interpret.”</p>
<p>“Who cares about statistics? Love isn’t measurable. Numbers suppress creativity.”</p>
<p>“Not true!” sayed Numms, a idiot savant who can multiply 3 digit numbers in his head, likes making sculptures out of math symbols, and baking pis with exotic fruit filling.<a href="#fn5" class="footnoteRef" id="fnref5"><sup>5</sup></a> “Every number has a personality. The number 868, for example, is the the pain of a person curled up in the back of an ambulance as it blares at full speed. 179 is a upwelling of mysticism, for it is a serious of columns, each more ornate than the last.”</p>
<p>Rudii raised her hand for attention. “Return to the topic at hand. Do we agree that we can only concoct with people who show their uniqueness? Uniformists do not show their uniqueness, but Creativists do.”</p>
<p>We signalled our agreement through finger-snaps, cheers in various languages, and dances of joy.</p>
<p>“But <em>how much uniqueness to show</em>?” Lukko asked.</p>
<p>A debate followed between the Minimal and Maximalist Creativists. The Maximalists won because the Minimal Creativists stopped talking midway through, and instead responded by saying off-topic phrases such as “blueberry burls” and “capricious cranberries” until we ignored them. Lisa kept hurling questions like “Why the hell do you want these <a href="these-bachelor-monks-ii.html">Philsophocler freaks</a> to fall in love with you anyways?”, so we also ignored her. (By “we” I meant the two other people I ended up talking to; we had splintered into many groups at this point.)</p>
<p>We discussed what we could be doing during our visits to <a href="the-street.html">The Street</a> to facilitate instant concoction. We came up with so many things we could do! Many people, when they visit The Street, do boring things like talking about the weather, attempting to summarize themselves to strangers, chewing, or drinking their tea. We could instead fold origami, play cat’s cradle, bob our heads in tune with an imaginary waltz, ask the waiter if we could assist in anything (to playfully reverse the usual order of things), asking the waiter loudly and audaciously what the most <em>creative</em> thing on the menu is so that all can hear, swirl a finger across a glass rim to signal of a playfulness and desire for music, shift our eyes between the different paintings on the wall to signal creative restlessness, take out sand from our pockets to show our appreciation for a sunny vacation, or take out a snowglobe with one snowman from our pocket and stare at it to ambiguously symbolize loneliness and self-sufficiency. Unlike our normal Creating, we chose carefully orchestrated actions that we felt would represent our personality in the best possible light.</p>
<p>We also concluded that Melli’s Flows was best, and Deepsea Teas was worst. (No one can even see you in the booths! The waiters would forget you were there if they didn’t record the table was occupied on their clipboard.)</p>
<p>A long time has passed, though, since that meeting, without any success. Until…</p>
<h2 id="rudii-concocts">Rudii concocts</h2>
<p>Yesterday, at Melli’s Flows, when Rudii found an ant on the napkin holder, instead of doing “standard” things like crushing the ant or reporting it to management, Rudii noticed how it kept skirting the sides, looking for a way off, and then took her straw out of her drink and made a water slide for the ant.</p>
<p>“Wow!” said a boy in glasses, with a bag of books on his left shoulder. “Are you the kind of person that enjoys helping others and make their lives more flavorful at the same time?”</p>
<p>“Are you a book-lover and someone who doesn’t mind jumping to conclusions about other people in public?”</p>
<p>“Since you helped the ant, I wonder what your thoughts are on ‘feeding the squirrels’?” (Rudii was also wearing a shirt with a picture of a squirrel with an acorn.)</p>
<p>“The best gift we can give the squirrels is not food, but art. In fact, I’ve just been chaosing on how to make an artistic playground for the squirrels…”</p>
<p>Soon they were conversing madly. Timoo had a habit of drawing a box in the air whenever he voiced a thought, and Rudii would take the invisible box, open it, and show her reactions through exaggerated facial expressions. Timoo was incredibly well-read but not well-created<a href="#fn6" class="footnoteRef" id="fnref6"><sup>6</sup></a>, and Rudii helped him “think outside the box” by taking a book from his bag, opening to a random page and reading a sentence, and asking him to continue the story. They shared their impressions of everyone within their line of sight, and found that Timoo’s impressions were more colorful, and Rudii’s more accurate.</p>
<p>I learned of this only later. Chyme ran into the Scoop, shouting, “Happened, finally! Ants, squirrels, boxes, acting, books and random quotes! Rudii!”</p>
<hr>
<p>The table of Creativists looked at her expectantly. They didn’t butt in because the acrobatics of Chyme’s associative memory were beautiful if allowed to run their course.</p>
<p>“Hands whirring like gears. Their words bubble incessantly like a brook. Others bounce around like ping-pong balls but they’re in stable orbit. Beware of biting fish.”</p>
<p>“Melli’s Flows!” Someone burst out.</p>
<p>“Instant concoction!” Someone else completed the picture.</p>
<p>The whole table of Creativists expressed their happiness (by snapping fingers, cheering in various languages, dancing in joy, pulling a paper bag with a smiley face over eir head, clinking mugs, or delivering an impromptu sonnet), and then followed Chyme to Melli’s Flows.</p>
<p>“Don’t worry, Trevisia, we’ll come back to wash our mugs!”</p>
<p>I wanted to follow, but it was my shift at the Scoop! I imagined them huddling at the windows of Melli’s Flows, watching; the bouncer coming out to tell them, “Are you in or out?”; Creativists influxing into the cafe, spicing up the conversation as they flit between tables, all the time secretly shooting glances at Rudii and her fellow concocter and slipping them creations like surreally painted hearts, or two stuffed squirrels hugging each other (the Creativists provided the greatest entertainment, as Timoo and Rudii were currently in their game of trying to judge everyone in sight, and everything she said was heard from some Creativist).</p>
<p>I did not completely miss out, though. Later Rudii and Timoo came to the Scoop, where I had the honor of feeding them many fresh cookies I had concocted from a perfect blend of flour, vanilla, cinnamon, oatmeal, butter, raisins, and love. Rudii, who normally ate one slowly and delicately, instead ate five in quick succession.</p>
<p>“Was it from the Creativism?” I asked Rudii when the rest of the Creativists had left.</p>
<p>“I don’t know. I think I just got lucky.”</p>
<p>Certainly Creativism helped. If Rudii hadn’t been a Creativist, she might have crushed the ant or reported it to management, and nothing would have happened.</p>
<p>I thought, if Rudii had so much success as a Minimalist, what could us Maximalists accomplish? Rudii did one one or two interesting things each time she visits Melli’s—what if we did ten, or a hundred? The more you create, the more chances you have to be lucky. If you keep doing interesting things, certainly one of those things will catch the eye of your future fellow concocter!</p>
<p>We sent a message to Dave that the Creativists now have one more success in love. Dave, however, said that the results still weren’t statistically significant.</p>
<p>Fellow Creativists: keep showing your creative selves. Each creation is another chance for instant concoction!</p>
<section class="footnotes">
<hr />
<ol>
<li id="fn1"><p>Words like “partner” or “lover” are mundane, suggesting cliched pictures of domestic life or desperate affairs. As Rudii would say, they suggest a role to be filled. “Fellow concocter” instead suggests someone who will Create things with you.<a href="#fnref1">↩</a></p></li>
<li id="fn2"><p>i.e., meeting. “Chaosing” means “brainstorming”. Many people approach brainstorming in an orderly fashion, such as sitting down in front of an empty notebook with a pen. “Chaosing” better captures our process.<a href="#fnref2">↩</a></p></li>
<li id="fn3"><p>This is typical of Creativist yearbooks, so we really need a Historian! Please please please apply. I know you all would rather be creating things rather than reading and organizing old things, but it would really be a service to Creativism…<a href="#fnref3">↩</a></p></li>
<li id="fn4"><p>I forged those. I wished I hadn’t burst out laughing when Lisa read them.<a href="#fnref4">↩</a></p></li>
<li id="fn5"><p>Like many other Creativists, I hated math before I met Numms. However, after seeing his colorful, anthropomorphized, surreal sculptures of digits hanging around the Workshop, I’ve liked them a lot more. It seems tragic, though, that modern math replaces all numbers with a Uniform <span class="math inline">\(x\)</span>.<a href="#fnref5">↩</a></p></li>
<li id="fn6"><p>the last time he drew a picture was in tenth grade, and despite all the books he’d read, he’d never written a single one himself.<a href="#fnref6">↩</a></p></li>
</ol>
</section>

  </div>

    

    <!-- Previous/next post-->
    <div>
    
    <a href="/posts/housing-optimization.html" style="float:left;">Previous post</a>
    
    
    <a href="/posts/emergency-chaosing.html" style="float:right; text-align: right;">Next post</a>
    
    </div>
    <br>

    <!-- Extension : Sharing buttons @ www.sharethis.com -->
    <span class='st_facebook_large' displayText='Facebook'></span>
    <span class='st_twitter_large' displayText='Tweet'></span>
    <span class='st_googleplus_large' displayText='Google +'></span>
    <span class='st_reddit_large' displayText='Reddit'></span>
    <span class='st__large' displayText=''></span>

    <div id="disqus_thread"></div>
    


  
    <script>!function(d,s,id){var js,fjs=d.getElementsByTagName(s)[0],p=/^http:/.test(d.location)?'http':'https';if(!d.getElementById(id)){js=d.createElement(s);js.id=id;js.src=p+'://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js';fjs.parentNode.insertBefore(js,fjs);}}(document, 'script', 'twitter-wjs');</script>
  </div>
  
</div>
]]></summary>
</entry>
<entry>
    <title>Housing Optimization</title>
    <link href="http://holdenlee.github.io/philosophocle/posts/housing-optimization.html" />
    <id>http://holdenlee.github.io/philosophocle/posts/housing-optimization.html</id>
    <published>2016-04-17T00:00:00Z</published>
    <updated>2016-04-17T00:00:00Z</updated>
    <summary type="html"><![CDATA[
<div class="container">
  <div id="content">
    <div class="page header">
      <h1>Housing Optimization</h1>
    </div>
    <div class="info">
      
       
        <p class="subs">by Fron
	</p>
      
       
        <p class="subs">on 2016-04-17
	</p>
      
    </div>
    
  </div>
  <!--/div-->

  <hr>

  

  <div class="blog-main">
    <p>When I <a href="/posts/how-i-became-a-uniformist.html">walked out of the Ideologies Fair</a>, I thought I would never see my shirt ever again.</p>
<!--more-->
<p>Imagine my surprise when the next day, I woke up to see my roommate, Lukko, wearing that monstrosity! Very briefly my vision was blasted with a riot of color displayed like the petals of some putrid, carnivorous jungle flora and glitter-glue constellations splayed out like the tentacles of some interstellar <em>lusus naturae</em> with too many plastic eyes, before I covered my eyes away and yelled, “Where did you get that?!”</p>
<p>“Trevisia gave it to me,” he said.</p>
<p>It struck me that Lukko had been the one warbling “opera” at the Ideologies Fair. So excited had I been during Orientation that I had not bothered to commit my roommate’s face to memory, and hence had failed to recognize him at the Fair.</p>
<p>“Please don’t wear that. It’s offensive to me, and it doesn’t belong to you.”</p>
<p>“It does, because you donated it to the Creativists,” Lukko said, “And I will wear it to remind you of your creative side. The more you surround yourself with U’s, Frongo, the more you’ll forget there ever is such a thing as creativity.”</p>
<p>Lukko paced as he crunched his toast (because sitting down eating it would be “standard”). He swung a chain that held one of those Creativist wooden boxes (decorated with many pipe-cleaner arms to look like a primeval bacteriophage) that would spit out a prompt every thirty minutes. I would come to dread this effigy over the next week, going so far as to buy a phonograph and a record entitled “Calming music” and huddle besides the phonograph’s trumpet every thirty minutes.</p>
<p>“Besides, once you create something, it has a life of its own. You can never, ever take it back.”</p>
<p>Lukko became an avid Creativist. In fact, he was not a bad Creativist. He had a remarkable talent for painting portraits of people screaming, as well as adapting cookware and the Handy Man’s Tool Set into musical instruments.</p>
<p>Lukko would wear the monstrosity at least once every week. However despite my <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Unexpected_hanging_paradox">best efforts at logic</a>, I was unable to predict which day he would wear the shirt. Due to its multitudinous appendages, the shirt could not be washed, and its stench soon matched its ugliness.</p>
<p>You must be thinking how unlucky I was to be matched with Lukko. In fact, I discovered that it was hardly due to chance. Rather, our matching was the result of careful calculation! In order to explain, I must first discuss our housing system.</p>
<h2 id="housing">Housing</h2>
<p>Director Haus was a tall bearded man whose hat also served as a minimal functioning (but empty) birdhouse. When I visited Philosophocle three weeks before the start of the semester, I inquired about accommodations, and he was kind enough to give me a tour of the Housing Office.</p>
<p>The Housing Office was the exemplar of industry. The wall of the office was covered in architectural blueprints, which between them mapped out every habitable room in the University. Thumbtacks and paper squares covered the blueprints. But what what drew my attention was the twenty-five students, shuffling papers from large stacks to other large stacks, clipping them together in twos, threes, and fours, and placing them in shelves labeled “certain”, “likely”, “probable”, “only if nothing better”, and “???”. On the blackboard was a gigantic graph drawn from colored chalk with the title “Compatibility”.</p>
<p>So engrossed were they in their work that none of them looked up as we entered.</p>
<p>“Who are these people?” I asked.</p>
<p>Director Haus beamed at me.</p>
<p>“Meet the Housers. Every paper you see in this room is a survey filled out by one of our current or incoming students. The Housers sift through thousands of self-descriptions to determine the optimal arrangement of students in dorms. As you can see, Dave there at the board is drawing a graph of the compatibility/non-compatibility of all male students who had Woody as their first-choice dorm.</p>
<p>“This is no mere housing ‘lottery’. This is a housing <em>optimizer</em>. Through statistics, debates, and discussions over late-night tea, we find the globally optimum housing arrangement.”</p>
<p>“But Director, would it not be more efficient to use a computer? I remember seeing a computer in the Technology Department.”</p>
<p>Director Haus gave me a stern look. “We cannot remove the human element from housing. A computer program, it is true, will output an optimal matching given a value function. But how can we tell a computer all the values that are important to our <em>human</em> students in finding the perfect roommate? Twenty-five students who understand the intricacies of rooming are much more suited to the task. Who are the people who you most need in order to order to grow? The Housers will find them for you.”</p>
<p>“But the sheer amount of student-hours…!”</p>
<p>“Being a Houser is not just an office job, Fron. It is a privilege. Hundreds of students apply to be Housers every year. Besides, students who are Housers gain intimate familiarity with the incoming class. During the first week, Fron, you will be surprised to meet several upperclassman will be able to summarize your biography—provided you fill out the survey, of course.”</p>
<p>Although I believed that Director Haus’s view on technology was too critical<a href="#fn1" class="footnoteRef" id="fnref1"><sup>1</sup></a>, the Housers’ efforts endeared me. A university who cared so much about its students that upperclassmen would volunteer to find the best roommates for incoming students, and who went about such a trivial task with the utmost precision and rigor!</p>
<p>When I informed Haus that I had not received the survey, he immediately delivered a copy into my hand. I busied myself the next five minutes in filling it out.</p>
<p>“But Director Haus, do you match up students by common interests? Wouldn’t this make the living communities too homogeneous?”</p>
<p>“We have thought of everything,” Haus said, pointing to a question further down the page.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>How different would you like your roommate to be from you?</p>
<p>(Exactly the same) 1 2 3 4 5 (Completely different)</p>
</blockquote>
<p>I bubbled in 5 (foolishly).</p>
<p>The last question was “what other criteria do you have for a roommate, in order of priority?” I did not wish to further burden to the already very busy Housers, so instead checked the box at the bottom, which read,</p>
<br />
<form action>
<input type="checkbox" name="surprise" value="surprse"> <strong>Surprise me!</strong>
</form>
<p><br /></p>
<p>“Excellent!” Director Haus said, “I am always glad to meet someone who has an adventurous taste in roommates.”</p>
<h2 id="appeal">Appeal</h2>
<p>On that fateful form, I had not described myself in Uniformist or Creativist terms, or any of the religions of Philosophocle. I wonder, however, if the Housers had already predicted that I would be a Uniformist, and Lukko would be a Creativist. In either case, I now believe the Housing Optimization system to be deeply flawed.</p>
<p>When I appealed my housing to Director Haus, he invited me into the Housing Office (now empty of students but with its walls still covered in blueprints and thumbtacks) and offered me a cup of tea. Upon finding my housing survey, however, he frowned.</p>
<p>“You clearly stated a preference for someone completely different,” Director Haus said, “And the Housers have honored this preference.”</p>
<p>“But I am extremely dissatisfied!”</p>
<p>“Is this dissatisfaction mutual?”</p>
<p>“Well…”</p>
<p>The truth was that Lukko was not at all dissatisfied. “I’m glad for your presence,” Lukko had told me. “Trevisia has told me that the Creativist road is difficult, for there are many who judge and threaten me based on my creations. By your continual challenges towards my creations, I will grow stronger as a Creativist.”</p>
<p>Director Haus’s eyes wandered to the blueprint of Pondside. My thumbtack was gray, and Lukko’s thumbtack was red.</p>
<p>“You will do well to learn from Lukko,” Haus said severely, as if reading my thoughts, “At Philosophocle, we do not optimize happiess. If we desired a happy life, we would not spend our lives studying obscure subjects at a university. If we did, we would move to Las Vegas<a href="#fn2" class="footnoteRef" id="fnref2"><sup>2</sup></a> or Barbados. We are here, Fron, because we desire intellectual growth.”</p>
<p>Our conversation was at an end. If I had talked with Haus after taking Introduction to Debate, I would have a comeback. But alas, I was an ignorant freshman. For a moment, I imagined going berserk, tearing down the blueprints on the walls and screaming, “we are humans, not thumbtacks!” As it was, I finished my tea and meekly left the Housing Office, leaving Director Haus to his architectural solitude. For the next year, until the next Housing Optimization, the Uniformists would be my primary source of solace.</p>
<section class="footnotes">
<hr />
<ol>
<li id="fn1"><p>Said Director Haus, “It is true that Computer Science is taking over many universities and diverting millions of dollars, but we at Philosophocle believe that <em>Human</em> Science is more important.”<a href="#fnref1">↩</a></p></li>
<li id="fn2"><p>A city in the United States known for a large population of Sexists.<a href="#fnref2">↩</a></p></li>
</ol>
</section>

  </div>

    

    <!-- Previous/next post-->
    <div>
    
    <a href="/posts/agnostic.html" style="float:left;">Previous post</a>
    
    
    <a href="/posts/creativist-love.html" style="float:right; text-align: right;">Next post</a>
    
    </div>
    <br>

    <!-- Extension : Sharing buttons @ www.sharethis.com -->
    <span class='st_facebook_large' displayText='Facebook'></span>
    <span class='st_twitter_large' displayText='Tweet'></span>
    <span class='st_googleplus_large' displayText='Google +'></span>
    <span class='st_reddit_large' displayText='Reddit'></span>
    <span class='st__large' displayText=''></span>

    <div id="disqus_thread"></div>
    


  
    <script>!function(d,s,id){var js,fjs=d.getElementsByTagName(s)[0],p=/^http:/.test(d.location)?'http':'https';if(!d.getElementById(id)){js=d.createElement(s);js.id=id;js.src=p+'://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js';fjs.parentNode.insertBefore(js,fjs);}}(document, 'script', 'twitter-wjs');</script>
  </div>
  
</div>
]]></summary>
</entry>
<entry>
    <title>Agnostic</title>
    <link href="http://holdenlee.github.io/philosophocle/posts/agnostic.html" />
    <id>http://holdenlee.github.io/philosophocle/posts/agnostic.html</id>
    <published>2016-04-12T00:00:00Z</published>
    <updated>2016-04-12T00:00:00Z</updated>
    <summary type="html"><![CDATA[
<div class="container">
  <div id="content">
    <div class="page header">
      <h1>Agnostic</h1>
    </div>
    <div class="info">
      
       
        <p class="subs">by Agnes
	</p>
      
       
        <p class="subs">on 2016-04-12
	</p>
      
    </div>
    
  </div>
  <!--/div-->

  <hr>

  

  <div class="blog-main">
    <p>While much of the student body is engaged in perpetual mock-wars between different religions (particularly the Creativists and the Uniformists), I would like to take the opportunity to offer an alternative: agnosticism.</p>
<p>People ask why I am agnostic. “Is it not terrifying, to have no solid ideals to stand on?” they ask me all the time.</p>
<!--more-->
<p>“It is like walking on a glass floor on the upper levels of a busy palace,” I tell them. It takes a while for them to imagine a glass floor, as they are used to floors of oak and concrete. “Part of me is afraid of the dizzying height, but another part of me stares with wide eyes at all the happenings revealed through the floor. To me, wandering through this palace and watching other people’s trajectories as they follow their religions is more enriching than following a religion of my own.”</p>
<p>They tell me my religion is close to that of the Wonderers. Indeed, the Wonderers are one of the groups closest to my heart. In case you do not know: they are the ones who you find walking outside in their pajamas when you get up to pee (or listen to PHSS) at 3am in the morning. Perhaps what keeps me from being a true Wonderer is that I have not participated in their insomnia gatherings, being fortunate enough to never have sleep problems (or unfortunate enough to not be able to stay up past midnight). Another philosophical distinction between us is that Wonderers believe very much in trying things, as evidenced by the American children’s book “Green Eggs and Ham” being on their reading list, while I take exception (as I am a vegetarian, there are many foods which I do not try, on principle).</p>
<p>Do you notice students who hold up signs advertising their religions after class and pass out handwritten brochures? Those of us who otherwise have trouble finding conversation partners at lunch know that we always have this recourse. Of course, with them we do not get to choose the topic of conversation. They have learned to talk fast, because they have learned from Introduction to Rhetoric not to give their listeners time to ask questions.</p>
<p>I have enjoyed many of these conversations. Zyndra offered a necklace with a Z made of pale blue stone that would rest coolly on my chest, explaining that as the last letter of the alphabet, Z represented the fact that all Zyndrian followers must have their eyes focused on the spot beyond the horizon, because everything before the last is ephemeral. She genuinely believed her own religion, unlike many of the students who proselytize as their homework assignment for Religion 101, whom I tend to avoid: for example, when I finished my conversation with Brent, he gave a sigh of relief that his homework had been accomplished. Other students, like Sankar, have constructed elaborate mythologies claiming divine inspiration. (I see that Professor Drim’s Awakening Your Creative Self class has been very successful.)</p>
<p>One proselytizer, angered at my unwillingness to convert after taking up several of her lunchtimes voicing doubts to statements she took for granted, told me, “Well, why don’t you start your own religion, and call it agnosticism?”</p>
<p>To her surprise, I took her comment seriously, though not literally<a href="#fn1" class="footnoteRef" id="fnref1"><sup>1</sup></a>, and decided to start a job as Counselor for Agnostics at the Wholebeing Center<a href="#fn2" class="footnoteRef" id="fnref2"><sup>2</sup></a>. (It was an interesting experience, filling out a job application for a job I invented myself. At the job interview, I explained to them what I would be doing, which, I am told, is the reverse of what normally happens.) The job has been a pleasure for me: many students who are unsure about which religion to follow want nothing more than a neutral party to listen to the conflicting voices inside their head, and I am more than happy to be the neutral party. For one hour, their heads become like the transparent floors of a glass palace and I am privileged to peer inside, before they once more draw their mental shades and become once more opaque to the world.</p>
<section class="footnotes">
<hr />
<ol>
<li id="fn1"><p>because to create a religion of agnosticism so would be a paradox of the same variety as “the set of all sets who do not contain themselves”, although I did for a moment imagine myself on the other side of the table, passing out brochures and preaching earnestly my true beliefs<a href="#fnref1">↩</a></p></li>
<li id="fn2"><p>editor’s note: formerly the Center for Physical and Mental Wellbeing, formerly the Health Center.<a href="#fnref2">↩</a></p></li>
</ol>
</section>

  </div>

    

    <!-- Previous/next post-->
    <div>
    
    <a href="/posts/how-i-became-a-uniformist.html" style="float:left;">Previous post</a>
    
    
    <a href="/posts/housing-optimization.html" style="float:right; text-align: right;">Next post</a>
    
    </div>
    <br>

    <!-- Extension : Sharing buttons @ www.sharethis.com -->
    <span class='st_facebook_large' displayText='Facebook'></span>
    <span class='st_twitter_large' displayText='Tweet'></span>
    <span class='st_googleplus_large' displayText='Google +'></span>
    <span class='st_reddit_large' displayText='Reddit'></span>
    <span class='st__large' displayText=''></span>

    <div id="disqus_thread"></div>
    


  
    <script>!function(d,s,id){var js,fjs=d.getElementsByTagName(s)[0],p=/^http:/.test(d.location)?'http':'https';if(!d.getElementById(id)){js=d.createElement(s);js.id=id;js.src=p+'://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js';fjs.parentNode.insertBefore(js,fjs);}}(document, 'script', 'twitter-wjs');</script>
  </div>
  
</div>
]]></summary>
</entry>
<entry>
    <title>How I became a Uniformist</title>
    <link href="http://holdenlee.github.io/philosophocle/posts/how-i-became-a-uniformist.html" />
    <id>http://holdenlee.github.io/philosophocle/posts/how-i-became-a-uniformist.html</id>
    <published>2016-04-07T00:00:00Z</published>
    <updated>2016-04-07T00:00:00Z</updated>
    <summary type="html"><![CDATA[
<div class="container">
  <div id="content">
    <div class="page header">
      <h1>How I became a Uniformist</h1>
    </div>
    <div class="info">
      
       
        <p class="subs">by Fron
	</p>
      
       
        <p class="subs">on 2016-04-07
	</p>
      
    </div>
    
  </div>
  <!--/div-->

  <hr>

  

  <div class="blog-main">
    <p>At Philosophocle, there are many paths. There are stairs angling proudly up the hills and sinusoids winding leisurely through the garden. There are zigzags of wheelchair-accessible alternatives, basement tunnels lined with hot-water pipes, ladders hung from trees designated good for climbing, forbidden rooftops (to be traversed only during power outages, when the electricity to the alarmed door cuts off). People have chosen their paths, like Jacob who always chooses the zigzagging path rather than the stairs even when he’s late for class, to remind himself “there are no shortcuts to life”, or Albert, who dreams of being a squirrel, and is still practicing his tree-climbing so he can make it across campus without touching ground.</p>
<p>As I entered the Ideologies Fair, I wondered: what would be my path?</p>
<!--more-->
<h2 id="my-encounter-with-creativism">1 My encounter with Creativism</h2>
<p>A huge crowd had gathered around the Creativist booth.</p>
<p>“Be Diferent! Be Divient!” their sign advertised.</p>
<p>On the left of the table were piles of plain white shirts. On the right was a box containing many tiny little wooden boxes. In the middle was a buffet table of decorations, including glitter, glitter glue, metal hooks, plastic eyes, pipe cleaners, bubble-letter tracers, a Random Quote Box, beads, thread, yarn, buttons, paint, spray paint, felt, sew-on-pockets, cardboard, cotton balls, flower petals, acorn caps, last autumn’s leaves, feathers dropped from birds in flight, and coconut shells.</p>
<p>“A lot of people tell you that you can benefit society most by following the standard path,” said a girl behind the table whose nametag read “Trevisia.”</p>
<p>“But we believe that a life with a single unique attribute is more well-lived than an unoriginal but helpful life. Of course, the more unique attributes the better. Creativism is simply creating, <em>ad infinitum</em>.”</p>
<p>“How can we join?” an enthusiastic freshman asked.</p>
<p>“As a warm-up you can design your own T-shirt,” Trevisia gestured to the buffet table. “Please make sure it is sufficiently different from everyone around you! Once you are ready, you will need to go through the <a href="how-i-became-a-creativist-ii.html">Initiation</a>…”</p>
<p>Trevisia was certainly unique. She wore a hat made of bread, two earrings upon which dangled wire letters A through Z, and a tie-dyed shirt filled with hundreds of eyes, from cyclopean to arachnid to plastic. She sported candy-cane striped hair.</p>
<p>I shifted uncomfortably under the stares of all those eyes. I pointed at her shirt and interjected, “What is the meaning of all those eyes?”</p>
<p>“No meaning,” Trevisia said, “But they do have names. This one is Cycloon, this one is Goliuth, this one is Arakaye, this one is eye4eye…”</p>
<p>I soon tuned out, as the fervent creating all around me led me to the question of, how would I decorate my shirt? My first thought was geometric shapes—but I looked at the boy next to me, and he had already drawn out a hyperbolic tessellation, with the animals of the zodiac embedded inside. I thought to make an acronym of my name, but Kakup had already done that (Kapricious and Kool under pressure). I thought to draw a coat of arms representing various aspects of myself, but the girl besides me had drawn not one but ten, arrayed in some genealogical tree of her identity.</p>
<p>Then I had a brilliant idea. The others had creative shirts, but the shirts were narrow in meaning and scope, like one of the many possible paths on campus. I would make a shirt that encompassed all the possible paths at once. I would use every single ingredient. Already I was mentally appropriating them: the glitter glue would be the stars; the coconut shell would be the Earth; the eyes signified all the life forms, terrestrial and extraterrestrial; last autumn’s leaves represented the inevitable decay of all things beautiful. Finding an empty bit of floor, I sat down and got to work.</p>
<p>It was not until thirty minutes later that I stretched out the shirt in front of me to examine my handiwork—with mounting horror. The shirt was not simply ugly, for it was worse than diseased reptile skin, which although ugly, is at least natural. I cannot describe the <em>object</em> I had created, except to say that even now, as I am thinking about it, I find myself scrunching up my face, breaking out in sweat, and grasping my knees to keep my body from shaking, until I remind myself of the <a href="PHSS.html">existence of luminescent jellyfish</a>.</p>
<p>“That’s beautiful!” Trevisia turned her multitude of eyes on me. “You would make a great Creativist. Why don’t you show the rest of the people here your creation—?”</p>
<p>Could it be? The Creativists were so starstruck with the act of creation that they would sing praises even when one of their kind created a monstrosity?</p>
<p>“Come back, Froggulon—Frobobbon? What was your name again?”</p>
<p>I hurried away, hiding my face. This was the final straw. The Creativists were not content at decorating shirts with all manner of unnatural appendages, they also had to decorate my name with all manner of unnatural consonants!</p>
<p>So eager was I to exit the Ideologies Fair that I would have barreled right through the exit had not I heard a voice, “Looks like we lost another one to the Creets!”</p>
<h2 id="saved-by-uniformism">2 Saved by Uniformism</h2>
<p>Eager though I was to escape the ignominy of unsuccessful creation, I would not have it be said that I was a “Creet”! The source of the voice was a girl behind a plain wooden table, in a gray shirt with a large black U in the middle. She had on a name tag with “My name is Not Important.” A boy sitting beside her had the same shirt, but with no name tag.</p>
<p>Noticing my attention, Not Important said, “Welcome, fellow student! May I see your shirt?”</p>
<p>I turned so I was facing the table. “What, this?” It was a shirt that said, PHILOSOPHOCLE: <em>A PINNACLE OF HIGHER EDUCATION</em> in lofty letters, amidst a background of clouds and pinnacles.</p>
<p>“No, the shirt you just made.”</p>
<p>Not Important winced and shielded her eyes. Unnamed stared at the shirt, looking but not seeing.</p>
<p>“My feeling is the same,” I assured Not Important.</p>
<p>Unnamed spoke up, “Such are the fruits of unbridled Creativism.”</p>
<p>After he spoke, I heard a beep. In front of the Creativist booth, someone stared intently at a slip of paper, before throwing it aside, and started warbling opera in a language that no human could understand. Not Important winced again. Unnamed handed me a pair of earplugs, which I gratefully plugged in. Not Important and Unnamed followed suit.</p>
<p>Unnamed offered me a T-shirt and a brochure.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>Every day the world around us pressures us to be unique—to talk in a different style of poetry in order to mark ourselves as having high artistic taste, wear clothing with designs no one has ever seen in order to win people’s praise for our fashionability, or to earn a grade that no one else has (like 100%) in order to be included in a “historical figure” box in the next edition of The Squirrel’s Guide to Philosophocle.</p>
<p>We are the Uniformists. We believe it is neither necessary nor virtuous to be unique. Uniqueness leads to egotism, triviality, frivolity, artistic confusion, a belief that the world is conspiring against you, and hallucinations.</p>
<p>Instead, we celebrate our common humanity. In a world where everyone is asking you to be different, we find solace in being the same.</p>
<p>Q: How can I join?</p>
<p>A: Wear a U-shirt and join our <a href="uniformist-lunch-table.html">daily lunch table</a>!</p>
</blockquote>
<p>“You should have been before the Creativists!” I told them after the opera finished. “Then I wouldn’t have wasted so much time making this shirt!”</p>
<p>Not Important and Unnamed looked at each other. “Unfortunately, the Activities and Ideologies Fair has two entrances. What’s ‘before’ to you is ‘after’ to someone else.”</p>
<p>“It would make more sense for one to be the Entrance and another to be the Exit, so everyone is moving the same direction,” I pointed out.</p>
<p>“But it wouldn’t be fair to impose Uniformity on everyone. Uniformity is a choice,” Not Important said.</p>
<p>“But the only reasonable one,” Unnamed added.</p>
<p>“Excusez moi,” Trevisia called from the adjacent table, “We’re running out of shirts. Will you give us some of yours? We’d pay for them, of course.”</p>
<p>“Absolutely not,” Unnamed said, “we can’t allow you to deface our pure shirts!”</p>
<p>Not Important cut in. “Un, Uniformists are supposed to be uniformly kind! I empathize with your lack of shirts, Trevisia, but I am afraid I cannot conscientiously sell our T-shirts if they will be decorated upon. What will students think, if they see U-shirts that have been painted with markers and plastic eyes? It will send a conflicting message about the meaning of ‘U’, and lead to fragmentation of our society.”</p>
<p>I started laughing. The scene was absurd. The Creativists still had glitter, glitter glue, metal hooks, plastic eyes, pipe cleaners, bubble-letter tracers, a Random Quote Box, beads, thread, yarn, buttons, paint, spray paint, felt, sew-on-pockets, cardboard, cotton balls, flower petals, acorn caps, last autumn’s leaves, feathers dropped from birds in flight, and coconut shells, but no shirts!</p>
<p>“It’s like making a bread with sugar and no flour. Or writing a thesis with pen but no paper!”</p>
<p>Unnamed held up a hand. “Do not use unsanctioned metaphors,” she said, “for what if they make it into the next edition of The Squirrel’s Guide to Philosophocle, and become a mark of distinction between the ingroup and outgroup?”</p>
<p>I was immediately chastised. Trevisia was still looking around frantically for shirts; her skills apparently did not involve Creating shirts out of thin air.</p>
<p>“You can have my shirt back!” I said, throwing my Creativist shirt at her.</p>
<p>“But Frokkoli—Frungular? Don’t you want to show your creative side sometime?”</p>
<p>I ignored her protests and walked smoothly out the door of the Ideologies fair. I had found what I had came for.</p>

  </div>

    

    <!-- Previous/next post-->
    <div>
    
    <a href="/posts/how-i-became-a-creativist-ii.html" style="float:left;">Previous post</a>
    
    
    <a href="/posts/agnostic.html" style="float:right; text-align: right;">Next post</a>
    
    </div>
    <br>

    <!-- Extension : Sharing buttons @ www.sharethis.com -->
    <span class='st_facebook_large' displayText='Facebook'></span>
    <span class='st_twitter_large' displayText='Tweet'></span>
    <span class='st_googleplus_large' displayText='Google +'></span>
    <span class='st_reddit_large' displayText='Reddit'></span>
    <span class='st__large' displayText=''></span>

    <div id="disqus_thread"></div>
    


  
    <script>!function(d,s,id){var js,fjs=d.getElementsByTagName(s)[0],p=/^http:/.test(d.location)?'http':'https';if(!d.getElementById(id)){js=d.createElement(s);js.id=id;js.src=p+'://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js';fjs.parentNode.insertBefore(js,fjs);}}(document, 'script', 'twitter-wjs');</script>
  </div>
  
</div>
]]></summary>
</entry>
<entry>
    <title>How I became a Creativist, II</title>
    <link href="http://holdenlee.github.io/philosophocle/posts/how-i-became-a-creativist-ii.html" />
    <id>http://holdenlee.github.io/philosophocle/posts/how-i-became-a-creativist-ii.html</id>
    <published>2016-04-02T00:00:00Z</published>
    <updated>2016-04-02T00:00:00Z</updated>
    <summary type="html"><![CDATA[
<div class="container">
  <div id="content">
    <div class="page header">
      <h1>How I became a Creativist, II</h1>
    </div>
    <div class="info">
      
       
        <p class="subs">by Trevisia
	</p>
      
       
        <p class="subs">on 2016-04-02
	</p>
      
    </div>
    
  </div>
  <!--/div-->

  <hr>

  

  <div class="blog-main">
    <p><a href="/posts/how-i-became-a-creativist.html">Part I</a></p>
<p>The Randomizer was a small wooden box. My first task was to decorate it. I strung together beads of all the colors of the rainbow and gave the box a showy tail; I covered the box with blue glitter glue; I bent several paper clips to make a wire head, filled in with two eyes of fake emerald<a href="#fn1" class="footnoteRef" id="fnref1"><sup>1</sup></a>, and added two confetti legs. It was no longer a box but a peacock. Randomizer was such a lame name, so I named him Peapocky, and hung him around my neck.</p>
<!--more-->
<p>“That is shit-tastic,” Lisa said, and then explained the initiation. Every thirty minutes the Randomizer—ahem, Peapocky—would beep, and a piece of paper would come out of his stomach. It would have a prompt such as “sing a song and dance a jig at the same time,” or “pretend to have a split personality,” or “make architecture” or “make an ad for a student club” or “say what you’re thinking out loud, in couplet form.” She told me the rules.</p>
<ul>
<li><p>After I pressed START, I must follow every instruction from Peapocky until he ran out of slips (about one week).</p></li>
<li><p>If I did not follow every instruction, Rudii, the Creativist Initiator and a psychology major with hawk-like eyes, would be able to tell from my fleeting facial expressions (or from a network of spies—Lisa couldn’t tell which), and I would be a “frigging-fracking-fugging failure.”</p></li>
<li><p>If Peapocky beeped in a public location, I was not allowed to move to a private location.</p></li>
<li><p>I could turn Peapocky off only during class and sleep.</p></li>
</ul>
<hr>
<p>Peapocky first beeped when I was walking to Introductory Philosophy the next morning. I picked up the slip of paper which had dropped to the gravel path.</p>
<p>“Interact with an animal only you can see,” it said.</p>
<p>But there were students around me everywhere! I closed my eyes and thought about not listening to Peopocky. But then I imagined Rudii’s spies watching me from a secret window. I imagined Lisa, at the end of the week, saying “Sorry, sissy-ninny, you shit-tastically flunked, I’ll have to take your Pee-poo-kooky-thing back.”</p>
<p>But then I remembered: I’ve always wanted to have a hedgehog as a pet. I would paint his quills rainbow (so that even though he was rolled up he would be beautiful) and name him “Heggymony”.</p>
<p>When I opened my eyes, I imagined Heggymony had gotten lost in the throng of students stampeding to class. I looked everywhere for him, asking passerby if they had seen Heggymony. I followed a trail of quills until I found him and screamed, “Don’t step on Heggymony!” and shielded him from the tens of trotting and trampling student feet. I went down on my hands and knees and scooped him up, tickling him and cooing so that he would uncurl and show his bright little face, with his two dark pools of silently observing eyes, to the world. I stroked his quills as I sat down, like an island in the middle of a stream, and said his favorite line, “Individual elements, moving at random, pose no threat to the Heggymony.”</p>
<p>Only then did I redden, expecting a crowd to have formed around me, around the girl taking to air.</p>
<p>But, to my surprise not a single student had stopped or even seemed to notice, except for the girl who had almost tripped over Heggymony and said, “Watch it!”</p>
<p>Over the next week, during the Creativist Initiation, I went through three phases.</p>
<ol type="1">
<li><p><strong>Fear</strong>: I expected the other students to point, laugh, and say, “Trevisia, have you gone nut-so?” or “What is the meaning of that song-and-jig?” or “Trevisia, may I take you to the Center for Physical and Mental Wellbeing?” I expected the gardener to rush over and tell me to vacate my bench because I was spoiling the peaceful environs. I so dreaded Peapoudolis’s beep, and even considered burying him at the bottom of my bookbag. I didn’t do so, only because I feared even more being rejected by the Creativists.</p></li>
<li><p><strong>Peace</strong>: After two days of no one telling me I had gone nut-so, my fears evaporated like dewdrops. The beeps became a law of nature. When I heard them, I didn’t panic, but slowly picked up the fallen slip of paper. My mind, rather than acting like a flock of pigeons who had just landed on a live electrical wire, reacted like a flock of pigeons conducting an aerodynamic show.</p>
<p>It was at this time that I started noticing the other to-be-Creativists carrying out their initiations. A girl recited a poem praising the clouds as she acted out a tae-kwon-do-like move. A boy’s two hands acted out characters hurling insults at each other as they battled with pencils. Another boy decorated the lamps and chairs around him with paper butterflies topped with glitter that he had stashed away in a little wooden box with wings. A girl took colored chalk from a little wooden box she wore on a bracelet and decorated the sidewalks with an advertisement for the “Underwater Breathing Society.” A person of neutral sex created an impromptu maze for an ant that had the misfortune of crawling on the desk at thirty minutes past the hour.</p>
<p>Some of their eyes were clouded by fear, and didn’t see me. Others had reached a Zen-like state. I gave them smiles to neutralize the Uniformist hostility. We shared a secret solidarity, even though we never talked, each busy with our own Creating.</p></li>
<li><p><strong>Anger</strong>: How could I not have seen the other Creativists before this week? The answer dawned: Such was the power that the Uniformists and Classicists had over Philosophocle that they had blinded me to all the uniqueness in plain view! The other students weren’t ignoring us out of spite—like pre-Creativist me, they didn’t even <em>see</em> us! I wanted to shout at them, holding back only because of the no talking signs in the library.</p>
<p>And it <em>wasn’t</em> true that nobody paid us any mind. During our Creatings, Some people shot us laser-like looks of ambiguous meaning. They had U-shirts on. I wanted to scream made-up curse words at them, but checked myself, because although Lisa was truly a friend (not just a conversation partner as she claimed), I had no desire to be the same as her. I contented myself with scowling, experimenting with all the different ways I could contort my facial features.</p></li>
</ol>
<p>I’m sure that when Rudii inspected me one week later, the fire in my eyes gave me away. She nodded in approval. I was finally a Creativist.</p>
<p>What is it like to become a Creativist, you ask?</p>
<p>It was as I was seeing in color for the first time. It was as if I had turned into a squirrel, and the trees on campus were no longer just trees, but towers with trellises, terraces, and turrets, their burls and whorls the faces of woodland gods.</p>
<section class="footnotes">
<hr />
<ol>
<li id="fn1"><p>One does not need precious gems to create art. All Creativist materials are cheap, because it is not the starting point, but the creating that is important.<a href="#fnref1">↩</a></p></li>
</ol>
</section>

  </div>

    

    <!-- Previous/next post-->
    <div>
    
    <a href="/posts/how-i-became-a-creativist.html" style="float:left;">Previous post</a>
    
    
    <a href="/posts/how-i-became-a-uniformist.html" style="float:right; text-align: right;">Next post</a>
    
    </div>
    <br>

    <!-- Extension : Sharing buttons @ www.sharethis.com -->
    <span class='st_facebook_large' displayText='Facebook'></span>
    <span class='st_twitter_large' displayText='Tweet'></span>
    <span class='st_googleplus_large' displayText='Google +'></span>
    <span class='st_reddit_large' displayText='Reddit'></span>
    <span class='st__large' displayText=''></span>

    <div id="disqus_thread"></div>
    


  
    <script>!function(d,s,id){var js,fjs=d.getElementsByTagName(s)[0],p=/^http:/.test(d.location)?'http':'https';if(!d.getElementById(id)){js=d.createElement(s);js.id=id;js.src=p+'://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js';fjs.parentNode.insertBefore(js,fjs);}}(document, 'script', 'twitter-wjs');</script>
  </div>
  
</div>
]]></summary>
</entry>
<entry>
    <title>How I became a Creativist, I</title>
    <link href="http://holdenlee.github.io/philosophocle/posts/how-i-became-a-creativist.html" />
    <id>http://holdenlee.github.io/philosophocle/posts/how-i-became-a-creativist.html</id>
    <published>2016-03-30T00:00:00Z</published>
    <updated>2016-03-30T00:00:00Z</updated>
    <summary type="html"><![CDATA[
<div class="container">
  <div id="content">
    <div class="page header">
      <h1>How I became a Creativist, I</h1>
    </div>
    <div class="info">
      
       
        <p class="subs">by Trevisia
	</p>
      
       
        <p class="subs">on 2016-03-30
	</p>
      
    </div>
    
  </div>
  <!--/div-->

  <hr>

  

  <div class="blog-main">
    <h2 id="trivia-night">1 Trivia night</h2>
<p>“Trevisia, you must be good at trivia! Why else would you be named so?”</p>
<p>After a semester and a half of failing subjects from Classical Painting to Introduction to Debate, I was desperate to find my calling.</p>
<p>“I’m no good at exams,” I told my roommates.</p>
<p>“These aren’t like exam questions. The questions in trivia nights are <em>unusual</em>.” <!--more--></p>
<p>They wouldn’t tell me how, though. As we walked to the <a href="the-street.html">Electric Eel</a>, I imagined the trivia-masters would ask questions such as identification of unusual colors, or the eight elements named in the Faerie Sonnets, or the right ratio of baking powder to baking soda in banana bread, that I would be uniquely able to answer.</p>
<p>But the masculinity of trivia appalled me. Trivia brought out the vilest parts of people. They tried to regurgitate answers that had been memorized from encyclopedias, newspapers, PHSS, the Internet, professors, missed questions on exams, word of mouth, or the “fact sheets” posted around campus and at the bus stop (for those who forgot to bring a book to pass the time).</p>
<p>I felt as if I were among <a href="uniformist-lunch-table.html">Uniformists</a>, except worse, because they were rowdy, all raising their hands, pounding on the tables, and clinking iced cubes in their drinks. I could feel the same answer being echoed in half the minds, even though I did not know what the answer was. Every time the Great Danzini directed a question at me, I came up with a random name, such as “Jeanatta Wullis” or “Ruthner Quorcum”. Unfortunately, not a single one was right. It was as if I was standing on one of the rings of Neptune, trying to throw a dart to hit exactly the pinnacle of Philosophocle.</p>
<h2 id="a-free-friend">2 A Free Friend</h2>
<p>After trivia night I decided to cash in my “free 3am friend” coupon. The girl behind the counter looked tired and pugnacious.</p>
<p>“I have a coupon…” I said tentatively.</p>
<p>She picked up the phone on her desk and dialed.</p>
<p>“Hey Agnes, we have a befriendee here…”</p>
<p>She gave me the phone.</p>
<p>“What would you like to talk about?” came the voice from the other end.</p>
<p>I took a deep breath. “I’m having this crisis, I just went to trivia night at the Electric Eel, and if I were to compare myself to a tree, each question they asked me wounded me like a swing of an ax…”</p>
<p>“I’d love to help you,” came the voice at the other end of the line, “but I’m helping someone deal with a breakup right now. I grant that losing at trivia night is a bad experience, but wouldn’t you say it’s a bit more… trivial? Give the phone back to Lisa, she can find you someone else.”</p>
<p>Lisa dialed another number (no response), and another (already busy with a befriendee). She checked the charts, “Joe takes the 3-4am shift off to listen to the <a href="PHSS.html">radio hour</a>, Jannie and Lura are out of town this week… I hate to say this, but we don’t have any befrienders available today.” She wrung her hands. “Looks like the world is just shitting on you today, you literally came the only time that we don’t have a single person available. I’ll give you a rain check on that, you can come for a free friend anytime… Here, why don’t you listen to the radio, perhaps it will have some ‘Mellow beats’ like last week.”</p>
<p>But instead it was some kind of primal screeching accompanied by clangs of metal.</p>
<p>“You sucking dicktail!” Lisa shouted at the radio, banging it against the table. “All I ask is some calming music and you give me this piss!”</p>
<p>Usually I don’t like caustic personalities. But somehow, at this unreal time, it seemed exactly what I needed. Lisa felt like someone flailing, beautifully. Like a dancer performing on the edge of a fountain, giving the illusion of falling but never actually falling. Like me, except that I would actually fall in.</p>
<p>“What about you?” I asked hesitantly, “Can’t you be my 3am friend?”</p>
<p>“Absolutely not! I’m the receptionist only. Though I don’t know why the freaking leaking hellspont I signed up for the job. Actually I do—it’s related to a social experiement—oh never mind. I’m not accredited, last time I tried it I made the befriendee cry.”<a href="#fn1" class="footnoteRef" id="fnref1"><sup>1</sup></a></p>
<p>She sipped a cup of fragrant black liquid.</p>
<p>“What is that?”</p>
<p>“This? Coffee. You’ve never had coffee before? Oh, you’re missing out, girl. Here, why don’t you have a cup. We can’t be friends, but we can be conversation partners. Is that good enough for you?”</p>
<p>Over the strangly energizing liquid I poured out all my troubles to Lisa. It turned out that the trivia night was just the tip of the iceberg that my ship had run into. Everywhere in Philosophocle I saw the unbending necessity to memorize equations, or “recall the classics”. Professor Klausicus told us that “we never make anything new, all we do is regurgitate the olds. Therefore, I will teach you to regurgitate the best of the olds.” When I told him that I made new names every day for fun, was that not “new”? he gave me a stern look and a tap on the knuckles, “Besides the mountains of literature, that does not even amount to a sand speck.” When I signed up for painting class, I imagined myself drawing winged horses, castles built from coral reefs, or aurora boreali, but the teacher insisted everyone drew the same apple, and graded us on realism!</p>
<p>When I wandered around campus for three hours in a daze after “trivia night”, it was not because of the stress of answering trivia questions under pressure nor the “iced tea”, but rather the combined pressure of my Philosophocle education thus far.</p>
<p>Lisa looked at me grimly.</p>
<p>“It seems like you need to meet the Creativists.”</p>
<p>She stood up.</p>
<p>“I’m closing tonight, as all our ‘friends’ are busy or slacking. Let’s go take a walk.”</p>
<h2 id="the-religions-of-philosophocle">3 The Religions of Philosophocle</h2>
<p>I told Lisa how my dormmates were Uniformists who kept pressuring me to join. They had donated all their old clothes to charity and replaced them with a wardrobe of U-shirts. How I shudder to think of a wardrobe being replaced like that! Imagine my rainbow colored shirts—one for each day of the week—all replaced by a uniform gray! As my three roommates descended deeper into Uniformism, I could no longer tell them apart. They would all eat breakfast together—identical slices of toast and cups of milk, everything—and I’d be along in my room, eating my box of Fruity Puffs. They’d all be smiling when they saw me, offering to lend me one of their U-shirts.</p>
<p>Not to mention, when we arrived at trivia night, they joined their Uniformist friends.</p>
<p>“Come join us,” they had said, but I refused, and was team-less.</p>
<p>“What a backhanded ploy to get you to joint the Uniformists!” Lisa said, “I’m glad you didn’t give in. But how could you miss the Creativists? Weren’t you at the Ideologies Fair at the beginning of the year?”</p>
<p>“Yes. It was so threatening, though! When I went in, the Theoreticians and the Applications were screaming at each other, and both of their presidents appealed to me to pick a side. I just backed out the door. As I was leaving, though, someone came up to me and gave me a coupon for a free friend.”</p>
<p>I noticed some ghostly figures drifting across campus. The two leaders had blankets draped over their shoulders.</p>
<p>“Who are they?” I asked.</p>
<p>“The Wonderers. You really missed everything at the Ideologies Fair, didn’t you? It’s alright, I’ll give you an overview.” She pointed at the stars. “What does that look like to you?”</p>
<p>I squinted. I tried to make out a deer, a wok, a stairway to heaven, a snake eating its own tail, anything, but came up with “a glob?”</p>
<p>“Exactly. So that’s the Uniformists, there.” She pointed at various constellations as she rattled off the groups. “Then you have their arch-enemies, the Creativists, see how that’s a person singing, dancing, and waving a paintbrush at the same time? That dark patch—there’s the Self-Effacers, you won’t see them much. Then there are the Techies and the Naturies, the Society for Family Values, the Sexists<a href="#fn2" class="footnoteRef" id="fnref2"><sup>2</sup></a>, and the Poly House, the Vegetarian Co-op and the Omnivorous Co-op, the Existentialists, Nonexistentialists, Rationalists, Utilitarians, Relativizers, Altruists, Egoists, Feel-Gooders, Faithers, Experimentalists, Unknowers, Choosers, Stoners<a href="#fn3" class="footnoteRef" id="fnref3"><sup>3</sup></a>, Freewillers, Determiners, Probabilists…”</p>
<p>We ducked under an archway of two kissing trees and came to a humble blue doorway. Lisa fiddled with the lock and the door opened. She struck a match and lit a lantern hanging beside the door.</p>
<p>“This is <a href="the-scoop.html">the Scoop</a>. There aren’t any cookies here now, though there is some delicious cookie dough in the fridge. But the real exhibit is downstairs.”</p>
<p>Just looking at the cafe for a few seconds under the dim light, I could tell it was a friendly place. The walls were chalkboards upon which students had wrote poems that I did not recognize as part of the “classics”. Unlike the identical, industrial stools of the Electric Eel, the chairs were all flawed in their own way, like individual people.</p>
<p>After Lisa fed me some cookie dough, we went to the Workshop in the basement.</p>
<p>There were three long tables, filled with art supplies like glitter, glitter glue, scissors, metal hooks, plastic eyes, pipe cleaners, bubble-letter tracers, a Random Quote Box, beads, thread, yarn, buttons, colored pencils, paint, spray paint, construction paper, felt, cardboard, burnt-out light bulbs, cut-out book covers, magazines, shells, stones, clay, sketch books, craft books, pop-up books, T-shirts awaiting color, used-up toilet paper rolls, starcharts, toothpicks, cotton balls, socks, flower petals, acorn caps, last autumn’s leaves, feathers dropped from birds in flight, and coconut shells. The floor was covered with old newspaper. There was a U-shirt hanging from a clothesline, which had been defaced by the addition of a set of arms and legs to the U. (I saw then, crystal clear, what U meant: it was an empty receptacle, waiting to be filled, incapable of filling itself.) There was a half-decayed mushroom palace, made from the fruits of a mycological expedition.</p>
<p>The whole place smelled like alphabet soup. I smiled as I remembered long dinners of focused rearrangement, trying to find the most mellifluous combinations of phonemes despite a lack of vowels.</p>
<p>“Wow. Can I use this space?”</p>
<p>“You can if you are a Creativist. But you must complete the initiation before you can become a Creativist. Will you accept the challenge?”</p>
<p>I nodded. I didn’t trust myself to open my mouth to speak—if I did, I was sure that I would spew out a series of never-before spoken words. The language I knew seemed inadequate to express what I felt.</p>
<p>Lisa opened a drawer and took out a small wooden box with a handle. “This,” she said, “is a Randomizer.”</p>
<p><a href="how-i-became-a-creativist-ii.html">Part II</a></p>
<section class="footnotes">
<hr />
<ol>
<li id="fn1"><p>The befriendee had been a Uniformist whose girlfriend just broke up with him because he insisted on her joining Uniformism before they got married. Lisa had absolutely no sympathy for him. “It’s very difficult to be a Befriender,” she concluded, “You have to be able to be anyone’s friend, even if they have the complete opposite philosophy. I like to choose my friends and enemies, thank you very much.”<a href="#fnref1">↩</a></p></li>
<li id="fn2"><p>Webmaster’s note: In Philosophocle, the suffix -ist primarily means “someone who does or believes in…” rather than “someone who discriminates based on”<a href="#fnref2">↩</a></p></li>
<li id="fn3"><p>so called because when they meditate, they sit as still as stones<a href="#fnref3">↩</a></p></li>
</ol>
</section>

  </div>

    

    <!-- Previous/next post-->
    <div>
    
    <a href="/posts/running.html" style="float:left;">Previous post</a>
    
    
    <a href="/posts/how-i-became-a-creativist-ii.html" style="float:right; text-align: right;">Next post</a>
    
    </div>
    <br>

    <!-- Extension : Sharing buttons @ www.sharethis.com -->
    <span class='st_facebook_large' displayText='Facebook'></span>
    <span class='st_twitter_large' displayText='Tweet'></span>
    <span class='st_googleplus_large' displayText='Google +'></span>
    <span class='st_reddit_large' displayText='Reddit'></span>
    <span class='st__large' displayText=''></span>

    <div id="disqus_thread"></div>
    


  
    <script>!function(d,s,id){var js,fjs=d.getElementsByTagName(s)[0],p=/^http:/.test(d.location)?'http':'https';if(!d.getElementById(id)){js=d.createElement(s);js.id=id;js.src=p+'://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js';fjs.parentNode.insertBefore(js,fjs);}}(document, 'script', 'twitter-wjs');</script>
  </div>
  
</div>
]]></summary>
</entry>

</feed>
